<topics>


  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-h-h-holmes</id>
    <results>
        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84036012/1894-11-19/ed-1/seq-1/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>Philadelphia, Nov. 18 – Following the death of R.H. Holmes, also known as Howard, in Boston, a major insurance fraud scheme has been uncovered by detectives from the Fidelity Mutual Life Insurance Association.

            On September 3, a man's body was found at 1319 Callowhill Street in Philadelphia and was initially identified by the coroner as H.J. Pitezel. However, it has now come to light that this body was a substitute used in a plot to defraud the insurance company of $10,000.

            Attorney Howe, from St. Louis, appeared in Philadelphia with a young girl, claiming she was the daughter of the deceased. The insurance company, after exhuming the body to confirm its identity, was satisfied with the claim and reburied it. Attorney Howe then collected $10,000, the amount owed to Mrs. Pitezel.

            A month ago, an agent from the insurance company, while in St. Louis, learned key information that revealed a conspiracy. It turns out that Holmes and Pitezel had a relationship as lawyer and client. Holmes had been previously arrested under the alias H.M. Howard for obtaining goods under false pretenses. Further investigation showed that Holmes and Pitezel had worked together in Chicago during the World’s Fair, running a hotel where they used secret rooms to hide goods they had swindled from merchants. This hotel was called the “World’s Fair Hotel.”

            During this time, Pitezel took out an insurance policy with the Fidelity company, and Holmes followed suit a month later, both using promissory notes for the first payment. After some investigation, it was discovered that Holmes and Pitezel obtained a corpse from a New York hospital, brought it to Philadelphia, staged the death at the Callowhill Street house, and collected the $10,000 payout. Holmes was arrested in Boston, and detectives are now pursuing the other conspirators involved.</text>
        </result>
      
        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042461/1894-11-21/ed-1/seq-1/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>STRANGER THAN FICTION.
          Swindler Holmes' Career of
          Crime.
          A Full Confession of His Dark
          Deeds.
          He Deserves to Be Hanged a - Dozen
          Times Over.
          Defrauding of Insurance Companlas Re
          dnc.d to a Stttsaos— Mra. Pllzsl's
          Story —Lawyer Uowe
          Missing.
          By the Associated Press,
          Philadelphia, Nov. 20.—Tbe arch
          conspirator, H. H. Holmes, accompa
          nied by Mrs. Pitzel and a pretty woman
          who calls herself Mrs. Holmes, arrived
          in this city today in the custody of De
          tective Crawford and Special Agent Perry
          •of the Fidelity Mutual Life association.
          Mrs. Piizel's 16 year old daughter, Meda,
          and her 1-year-old bay were also with
          the party. Mrs. Holmes disappeared
          soon after her arrival, and no clue to her
          whereabouts could be obtained. It is
          thought she is stopping at a hotel in the
          neighborhood of police headquarters.
          After tbe arrival, tbe party was
          closeted with Superintendent of Police
          Linden until late in the afternoon.
          When the conference was over. Detective
          Crawford detailed the story of tbe trip,
          tbe moat important feature of which
          was the relation by Mr. Holmes of the
          story of bis whole life. It reads like
          tbe moat sensational of romances.
          Holmes Bat beside tbe detective with
          handcuffs on. The train had scarcely
          emerged from the Boston depot before
          lie iried to bribe hie captor. He offered
          the detective $000 if ho would allow him
          to escape. He said he had frequently
          hypnotized persons, having acquired the
          r.rt from a coliege professor in the west.
          He said he could get the money from
          his wife or Mrs. Pitzel. Wben ho caw
          his words had no effect, he entered into
          general conversation aud told the story
          of hia life.
          He said he was raised in Burlington,
          Vermont, and was co well educated in
          the schools that at 15 he was a tencher.
          For some time afterward he went to
          collegia there and later in Detroit, Micb.
          Here he formed the acquaintance of a
          medical student, who, he said, fur
          nished the body in New York in the
          present caee. He refused to divulge
          hie name. During vacations tbey wonted
          on farrae to ruiee their college expeuees.
          but one summer tbey found theuiGelves
          without means, and then the medical
          man suggested the idea of getting a
          body and beating nn insurance com
          pany. This was 12 years ago.
          The doctor got his life insured for
          $12,000. They obtained a body in Chi
          cago, took it east, arranged the details
          id identification and successfully got !
          the money with which they continued j
          their studies. He refused to name the -
          company thus swindled. They worked
          the scheme afterwards with sncceis,
          obtaining sums ranging from $10 000 to
          $20,000.
          j Once Holmes got bis life insured for
          [ $20,000 He then went to a hotel in
          Rhode Inland. At that time be wore a
          beard. He secured a corpse in Chicago,
          cut off the head and took tbo body to a
          lonely spot not far from tbe hotel.' Then
          he ehaved off his beard, returned to the
          hotel, asked for Holrr.es and engaged a
          room to wait for him. He bad brought
          the head with him and burned it be
          yond recognition in the fireplace of the
          hotel. This scheme, however, fell
          through, the mother of big wife, when
          she discovered the scheme, threatening
          to tell tbe police, and Holmes fled to
          the west.
          Resuming his story he said that while
          living in Chicago about 18 months ago,
          he tell in with a type-writer girl and
          furnished a house on the outskirts
          where tbey lived together. A younger
          sister came to visit them and the
          woman grew so jealous of her that in a
          quarrel one day she struck her over
          the head with a etool and killed her.
          To save the woman with whom he
          lived, Holmes said he put the body in
          a trunk loaded with stones and sunk
          it in the lake.
          This girl had property in Texas, and
          he and Pitzel took it off her hands and
          sent her abroad. It waa worth, he said,
          $40,000, and after getting it in their
          hands they went through Texas buying
          carloads of horses on notes on this prop
          erty, but as they never had a legal title
          to the property, the notes were worth
          less, and it is for this affair they are
          wanted in Fort Worth. To save this
          property Holmes said he and Pitzel
          formed tbo scheme of swindling the Fi
          delity company. He told the detective
          that for the crimes he had committed
          he deßerved to be hanged a dozen
          times.
          Holmes is not lacking for money, as
          he himself admitted that at the present
          time he ih supporting nearly two dozen
          persons, including the girl murderess,
          her mother and an imbecile brother,
          two orphans in Chicago who live in one
          of his properties, three separate alleged
          wiveß and their children rtnd his own
          mother and father in Kankakee. He
          would not give the names of the women.
          He firmly maintained that Pitzel ie
          alive and in Snn Salvador, and that he
          will hear from him through the personal
          column of a certain newepaper,
          Mr. Ferry said that ac a result of the
          interview it had been decided to arrest
          a number of other persona whose names
          were not ready to be given out.
          Mr. Perry related in detail the story
          of Holmes' arrest in Boston and the
          manner in which Mrs. Pitzel was de
          coyed from Burlington. He said tbat in
          the secret conference today nothing had
          been said that would in tbe slightest
          degree refute his original theory that
          Pitzel had been murdered. Wben in
          the west be saw tbe parents of Mrs.
          Pitzel, and tbey told him their daugh
          ter had complained of the exorbitant
          fee charged by the St. Loniß lawyer—
          $2500. In corroboration of his murder
          theory, Mr. Perry said tbat he had from
          Mrs. Pitzel an exact description of
          her husband, agreeing in every respect
          with that of the corpse found in the
          Oallowhill street hoose. Mrs, Pitzel, he
          continued, was perfectly innocent of
          any complicity in the whole affair. She
          told Perry last night that she had re
          ceived only $5000 in cash. She said
          Holmeß had taken $5000 of the money
          and put it in a speculation in Port
          Worth in which Pitz9l was also Inter
          ested. Holmes told Perry that this was
          true. In Texas, Perry said, Holmes
          operated under the name of H. H.
          Pratt. He added that Pitzel and B. T.
          Lyman are one and tbe same man.
          MRS. PITZEL'S STORY.
          Hho Fairs Bar Hmliiud Is Really Dead.
          M-r Daughter Missing.
          Boston. Nov. 20.—Mrs. Carrie Pitiel,
          it is claimed, has made a full confession
          of the alleged insurance swindle. It is
          stated that she hae implicated Holmeß,
          at whose suggestion, it is claimed, she
          went to Burlington, Vt. She stated
          that Holmee substituted tbe alleged
          bogus body for that of her husband and
          collected the insurance, but she was
          kept in ignorance of the whereabouts
          of her husband, who disappeared at
          once. Since the affair she has been
          roaming round from place to place,
          prompted by Holmee, in eearcti of her
          hueband, and it waa through the hope
          that she would be sent to him that Bhe
          answered the telegrams of the detec
          tives. Now ahe fears that the body for
          which the insurance was paid was not a
          bogus one, but that of her hnsband.
          Mrs. Pitzel aleo fears that her daugh
          ter, Alice, who was the only one besides
          Holmes t > identify tha body, has been
          spirited away, as Bhe has completely
          disappeared and Holmes is the last one
          known to have seen her. Holmes as
          serts be left Alice and tbe other Pitzel
          children at their father's home in
          Detroit a month ago, and since then has
          heard nothing from him.
          Holmee further stand that wben he
          came to Boston on 'Tuesday last be in
          tended to take paesage for Berlin, but
          changed his mind, and before he could
          perfect other plana the detectives bad
          him.
          HOLMES' VICTIMS.
          Good Reason to Believe He Murdered
          tbe Williams Sisters.
          Fort Worth, Tex., Nov. 20.—There is
          every reason to bolieve that C. H.
          Holmee, who went by tbe name of O. C.
          Pratt in Fort Worth, ia guilty of mur
          dering Minnie X, Wiliiame und her sis
          ter Ann. The crime waa probably com
          mitted in Chicago, and in this crime a
          man who claimed here to be a
          citizen of Chicago and called himself
          Benton T. Lyman, is an accomplice,
          Some time iv February be came here
          from Chicago and placed on record a
          deed from one Bond to Lyman for ICO
          feet front on Husk und Second etreete.
          Bond got title by deed from Minnie
          R. Wiliiame, executed before a no
          tary, whoan name was said to be
          HolmeD. Oa this property Lyman
          beaaii the erection of a three-story
          huilding. Lyman had sold one lot to a
          Fort Worth citizen who, fearing the title
          wae clouded, began to invest gate. He
          found that Minnie R. Wiliiame wrote
          late in 1803 to her sister Miss Ann Wil
          ium*, of Midlothian, Texas, to come to
          Chicago, tnat she v. a a going to bs mar
          ried and go to Europo. The sister left
          for Chicago. No word ever came from
          either of tbe Bistere.
          Minnie K. Williams, by will, was left
          half a block of property in tbe heart of
          Fort Worth, valued at $60,000, and a
          farm valued at $15,000. Thiß property
          has all been alienated, ostensibly by
          Miss Wiliiame. A detective has recent
          ly been sent to find the girls, but no
          trace can be discovered.
          </text>
        </result>

        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042461/1894-11-22/ed-1/seq-1/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>THE PITZEL MYSTERY.
            It Deepens as the Days
            Roll By.
            The Alleged Murdered Man
            Still Alive.
            Seen in Chicago Less Than Two
            Weeks Ago.
            Swindler Holmes' Trail of Crime—lie
            Was Often In Indianapolis- A.
            Third Woman Victim
            Discovered.
            By the Associated Press,
            Philadelphia, Nov. 21. —The Pitzel
            mystery deepens as time wears on. To
            day many theories in regard to the mys
            tery were knocked in the head by tbe
            announcement tbat 13. F. Pitzel, the
            supposed murdered man, was seen in
            Chicago less than two weeks ago. Pres
            ident Fouzof the Fidelity Life Insurance
            company said today:
            "This morning my Chicago represen
            tative telegraphed me tbat a Mr. Bryan,
            who is a bueiness man in Chicago, called
            on him and said that B. F. Pitzel was
            in tbat city less than two weeke ago.
            Mr. Bryan says be bas known Pitzel for
            many years, and had frequent business
            transactions with him, and it is impos
            sible fot him to be mietaken. When
            they met, Bryan did not know Pitzel
            wae euppoeed to be dead, and tbe two
            greeted each otber cordially and re
            paired to a near-by ealoon where they
            bad a drink together. Then tbey sep
            arated and Bryant saye he doee not
            know whether Pitzel was to remain in
            thecity or not. However, our men there
            and tbe Pinkerton detectives have taken
            up the clew, and it is my opinion that
            Pitzel will be produced within a few
            dayp."
            President Fcuz called on Mrs. Pitzel
            and her daughter at tbe Central station,
            tiday, and received valuable informa
            tion Irom tbe daughter in reference to
            her father. The daughter said she re
            numbered while walking with her fa
            ther one Sunday in Chicago that tbat
            latter bad said to her: "If you ever hear
            through the newspapers or any otber
            way tbat I iiave been found dead, do not
            believe it. I will be all right."
            Later on, while in Boson, she read
            the story ot her father's death in a news
            paper. As soon as she had finished the
            etory, Holmes said to her: "Do you re
            member what your father told you the
            afternoon you were walking in Chi
            cago?"
            Daring Mr. Fouz'e interview with the
            daughter, Mrs. Pilzal grew excited and
            exclaimed : "They have all deceived me,
            even my own daughter."
            Mrs. Pitzsl said she remembered re
            ceiving a letter from her daughter Alice
            in which she related her experience
            while coming east for the purpose of
            identifying her father's body. Alice
            etated that Howe and Holmes accom
            panied her and both were sociable with
            each otber on the trip east. This eets
            at reet the claim of Howe that be never
            met Holmes until introduced to him by
            President Fouz on hia arrival in this
            city.
            AT INDIANAPOLIS.
            Indianapolib, lad., Nov. 21.—1t devel
            oped here today that U. H. Howard,
            the insurance swindler, known ac
            Holmes and Mudgett, has been here
            often. On September 24th he brought a
            young girl with him, whose name he
            wrote on the register of tbe hotel ac
            Etta Pitzel of St. Louis. Howard ex
            plained to the clerk tbat she was ttie
            daughter of au old friend of bis who bad
            jdstdied, and he was taking her home.
            The clerk says be believes be has Been
            her on tbe streets since the time she
            was supposed to have left. She wae
            about 13 years old
            Lawyer Albert W. Wishard was in
            structed by telegraph from Philadelphia
            to rile suite lor tbe recovery of money
            obtained by H. M. Howard, now under
            arrest ot Boston, part of which is on de
            posit iv a bank in this city. Tbe title
            of the complaint filed is the Fidelity
            Mutual Liie association against H. H.
            Howard, alias H. M. Holmes, alias Her
            man Mudgett, aud Georgiana Howard.
            Ihe plaintiff alleges tbat be is engaged
            in the business of life insurance and
            that be issued a policy on the life of
            one B. F. Pitzel for sHi,OOO, and that
            by a mistake on tbe part of the
            plaintiff and deception and fraudulent
            representation on tbe part of the de
            fendant the said Howard received tbe
            sum of |10,000; that afterward the
            plaintiff discovered tbat B. F. Pitzel
            was still alive, proofs of tbe claims were
            spurious and fraudulent and made for
            the express purpose of cheating the
            plaintiff out of insurance money ; that
            ibe defendant fled tbe country, turning
            over and paying to his co-defendant,
            Georgiana Howard, a large portion of
            the $10,000 which the defendant depos
            ited in tbe bank in this city. An affida
            vit for a writ of attachment is also tiled.
            ANOTHER WOMAN VICTIM.
            Chicago, Nov. 21. —Following cloae on
            tbe atory of tbe mysterious disappear
            ance of the Wiliiame aiatera at tbe hands
            of Holmee, tbe life inenrance swindler,
            comes a (iiird woman victim, namely
            Miss Kate Durkee. Miss Durkee had
            property. Documents representing the
            property came into the bands of H. H.
            Holmes by theft. The woman mysteri
            ously disappeared, and Holmes showed
            title to the property. Mies Durkee was
            not Miss Williams; she bad dark eyes
            aud hair, while Miss Williams waa a
            blonde. A year ago today 25 creditors
            oi H. H. Holmes met at tbe office of
            George B. Chamberlain and made a des
            perate effort to find out who and where
            Miss Durkee was. It waa supposed she
            was an accomplice of Holmes; tbat
            property, illegally obtained waa being
            trauaferred to her name. Tbe creditors
            wished to reach it. Suddenly Kate Dur
            kee dropped entirely from sight, like
            tbe Williams sisters, and left no trace
            behind.
            "I believe she waa murdered," said
            Chamberlain today. "I believe also
            tbat both Williams girls wore mur
            dered."
            Mr. Chamberlain, as proprietor of the
            Lafayette Mercantile agency, began an
            investigation of Holmee a year ago.
            Mtss DUBKBK FOUND.
            Miss Dnrkee bas not been murdered,
            Sbe has been found in Omaha. A dis
            patch from that city tonight saye:
            Miss Kate Durkee, lives here in
            this city witb ber brother, who is
            assistant auditor of tbe Burlington rail
            road. She expreeeed aurpriee wben
            asked concerning ber connection with
            Holmes' family in Chicago. She never
            heard of but one wife. Hie recently
            visited Mrs. Holraea and made Holmee
            transfer a piece of property in Chicago for
            ber. She refused to explain what prop
            erty this was, hut declared that Holmes'
            Chicago lawyer was familiar with the
            deal.
            Attorney Duncombe of this city said:
            "Holmes employed me to attend to
            some business for him, and in the courae
            of the action for which I waa retained it
            became necessary to take the deposition
            of Miss Kate Durkee. In her evidence
            she eaid she waa related to the wife of
            Holmeß."
            Mr. Duncombe said he had frequently
            seen Pitzel in company with Holmes
            and that ho would know whether ttie
            corpse in question waa the body of
            Pitzel if be aaw it.
            PlTKlti'l OLD HOME.
            St. Joseph, Mo., Nov. 21.—8. F. Pit
            zel, who is the central figure in the
            Philadelphia insurance swindle, for
            which offense H. 11. Holmes is under
            arrest, is a former resident of this city,
            and left here about three years ago un
            der a cloud.
          </text>
        </result>

        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1895-07-16/ed-1/seq-1/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>Bodies of the Murdered
            Pietzel Girls Found
            in Toronto.
            THREE FIENDISH CRIMES.
            The Notorious H. H. Holmes
            Accused of Taking Their
            Lives.
            RECORD OF MANY KILLINGS.
            It Is Thought the Insurance Swin
            dler Had Murdered the Elder
            Pietzel.
            TORONTO, Ont., July 15.— The bodies
            of Etta, Alice and Hettie Pietzel, the miss
            ing daughters of Benjamin F. Pietzel,
            were found by Detective Cuddy of Toronto
            and Detective Greyer of Philadelphia, to
            day, buried in the cellar of the house
            No. 16 St. Vincent street. H. H. Holmes,
            now under arrest at Philadelphia, is be
            lieved to have deliberately murdered the
            girls after he had first murdered their
            father in Philadelphia and their brother in
            Detroit.
            Inquiries began by the police to-day and
            led to the knowledge that Holmes and the
            children lived at the house in question,
            and search was made by the two ottioers.
            A photograph of Holmes was shown to
            Frank N. Nudel of the Ontario Educational
            Department, who owns No. 16 St. Vincent
            street, and without hesitation he identified
            it as that of the man who had rented the
            house from him last October, and after a
            very short stay had departed.
            When they reached the cellar it appeared
            to the detectives that something had dis
            turbed the cellar floor, and arming them
            selves with shovels they began to dig. A
            short distance below the surface they came
            across the arm and a portion at the head of
            one of the girls, and further work soon re
            vealed the bodies of all of the victims.
            They were nude and apparently had lain
            there since last October.
            City Detective Inspector Stark was com
            municated with and gave instructions that
            the bodies be removed, and they were
            taken to Humphrey's undertaking estab
            lishment on Yonge street. Coroner Orr
            was informed of the ghastly discovery, and
            called an inquest to be held at Police
            Headquarters to-morrow night. It is un
            derstood that the jury will meet pro forma,
            and after viewing the bodies will adjourn
            for one week, to enable the Crown authori
            ties to work up evidence. The bodies of
            the little ones were buried three feet from
            the surface and were in a fair state of
            preservation.
            Holmes, the alleged murderer of the
            girls, is held in Philadelphia on a charge
            of conspiracy, and a nice legal point now
            presents itself. The murders have been
            committed in Canada, the accused
            must be tried within its boundaries, but
            as Holmes has pleaded guilty to one
            charge in the United States he may insist
            on being sentenced for that.
            H. H. Holmes, alias Harwam W. Mudg
            ett, alias H. H. Howard, was born in New
            Haven, Conn., and attended a medical
            school at Burlington, Vt.,and later at Ann
            Arbor, Mich. He was married at the
            latter place. He and a friend swindled an
            insurance company in Chicago om of
            $12,000 soon after graduating. They made
            another haul of $10,000 in a similar way.
            Holmes went into the drug business and
            speculated. His wife went home and he
            married another woman, with whom he
            went to California.
            Returning about a year ago, he went to
            housekeeping with the woman typewriter
            of the company, whose acquaintance he
            had formed. He tried to cheat a fire insur
            ance company out of $00,000, but failed,
            and learning that his typewriter and her
            sister had inherited $50,000 laid a scheme
            to ket the money. The sister came to live
            with them and suddenly disappeared,
            while he and Minnie, the typewriter girl,
            took up their abode at the Plaza Hotel,
            Chicago.
            Holmes next appeared in Terre Haute,
            Ind., where he bailed Pietzel out of jail.
            From there he went to Franklin, Ind.,
            where he married Miss Yoke, and they
            spent their honeymoon in Denver, where
            Holmes made $27,000 in speculation.
            At Philadelphia, later on, he and Fietzel
            played the last card. Pietzel wu insured
            in the Philadelphia Mutual for $10,000.
            On September 3 he was found dead in the
            house at 1316 Callowhill street, which he
            had rented under the name of B. F. Perry.
            His body was badly burned and the face
            was almost unrecognizable. Holmes and
            Pietzel's wife's children identified the body
            as Pietzel's, and $7500 of the insurance was
            paid over.
            Then Train-robber Hedgespeth gave the
            whole case away to Chief of Police Harri
            son because Lawyer Howe, whom he had
            got into the conspiracy, had not paid
            him the promised reward. Holmes was
            traced to Toronto, Burlington and Boston,
            and in the latter city was arrested. Mean
            while the Pietzel children haa disappeared,
            the boy being traced to Indianapolis and
            two girls to Toronto. Holmes awaits
            sentence in Philadelphia for insurance
            fraud, and the police expect to fix several
            murders on him.
            Doctors who have examined the bodies
            agree with Detective Grier's theory that
            the girls were killed by hypodermic injec
            tions of morphine. Holmes is known to
            be an expert user of injections. J
            HOLMES' RECORD.
            One of the Boldest Scoundrel* Ever Ar
            ralngrd for a Crime.
            PHILADELPHIA, Pa., July With
            the finding of the bodies of the Pietzel
            children in Toronto, a chapter in the his
            tory of one of the most sensational crim
            inal cases in the annals of this country is
            closed, and the net of the law is being
            drawn more closely " about one of
            the : boldest scoundrels . who have ever
            been arraigned at the bar of justice.
            Herman Mudgett. alias H. H. Holmes, is
            in the County Prison here awaiting sen
            tence to the confessed charge of conspiracy
            in defrauding the Fidelity Life Association
            of Philadelphia. out of $10,000 by palm
            ing off upon it a bogus body
            as that of Benjamin F. Pietzel, , a
            policy-holder of the company. The case
            exceeds in interest the most sensational
            novel ever written, and has so many sides
            to it that it ts difficult to even outline it in
            the ordinary length of a newspaper dis
            patch. ■;:
            ■ In July, 1889, tne Fidelity Life Associa
            tion issued a policy for $10,000 upon the
            life of Benjamin Pietzel. Shortly after
            this, a man giving the name of B. A.
            Perry rented a house at 1319 Cailowhill
            street, this city. In September of the
            same year a lire, shown to have been
            caused by an explosion, occurred at the
            house and the charred body of Perry was
            found.
            A short time after this Jephtha B.Howe,
            an attorney at St. Louis, presented a claim
            to the Fidelity Company for the $10,000 on
            the life of Pietzel, alleging that the man
            found in the house at 1319 Callow
            hill was Pietzel. With Howe were
            Alice, the 13-year-old daughter of Pietzel,
            and Holmes, the arch conspirator in the
            case. The body of the supposed Perry had
            beenburied in the potter's field, but was ex
            humed, and Alice and Holmes positively
            identified it as that of Pietzel. The money
            was paid to Howe and the party returned
            to St. Louis.
            Mrs. Pieteel was in St. Louis at this
            tini-', and through the representations of
            Holmes that she could aid her husband in
            furthering his interests, had consented to
            become a party to Holmes' scheme to de
            ceive the insurance company by passing
            off upon it a bogus body as that of Pietzel.
            Holmes told her that he and Pietzel had
            procured a corpse in New York and had
            had it up in the house at 1319 Cailowhill
            street and that this was the body found.
            Mrs. Pietzel believed this story, and to aid
            her husband consented to take part in the
            deception.
            The insurance company became sus
            picious, and setting detectives upon
            Holmes' track built up a case against him,
            and in November last year Holmes was
            arrested in Boston.
            A few days after Holmes' arrest Mrs.
            Pietzel was arrested in the same city and
            Howe was arrested in St. Louis. Holmes
            offered to relieve her of the burden
            of the three children. The oldest and
            the youngest child remained with Mrs.
            Pietzel and Holmes took the other three.
            Alice, Nettie and Howard. After parting
            with her children, Mrs. Pietzel has never
            been able to obtain from Holmes any defi
            nite Knowledge of their whereabouts.
            </text>
        </result>

        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90059522/1895-07-28/ed-1/seq-1/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>TELLTALE SKULLS
            GRUESOME REVELATIONS OF
            HOLMES? HORRIBLE OCCU
            PATION.V .: ,-*
            AN ARTICULATOR'S TALE.
            A MAN WHO WAS HIRED TO
            MOUNT THREE VIC
            TIMS.
            GRAVES IX THE QUICKLIME.
            Dnst of Two Women and Mats of
            Hair Found in a Bed of
            Clay.
            CHICAGO, July 27. — More con
            clusive evidence than has heretofore
            been collected by the police in the
            Holmes case was revealed by the
            investigation tonight. Inspector
            Fitzpatrick believes it to be certain
            that at least three murders were
            committed in the "castle" of Holmes,
            and through witnesses that were
            found today it is believed Holmes
            can now be convicted of murder in
            this city. The police have found a
            man, whose name they refuse to di
            vulge, but who was brought to the
            office of the inspector this afternoon
            by Lieut. Thomas and Officer Foley,
            of the Cottage Grove avenue sta
            tion. He told the police that he had
            mounted three skeletons for Holmes,
            and that the skeletons were from
            bodies taken from the house of
            Holmes on Sixty-third street. One
            of these he said was the body of a
            man, and the other two were wom
            en. They were taken from a dark
            room in Holmes' house in the night
            time, and two of the mounted skel
            etons were returned to Holmes. The
            flesh of the bodies had not been
            stripped from the bones when the
            bodies were given to the new wit
            ness, but the faces were so badly
            lacerated and torn that identifica
            tion would have been impossible.
            The police also found an expressman
            today who was able to give what the
            police think is important informa
            tion. The name of the expressman
            is Charles Humphrey, and in the
            month of June, 1893, he was hired
            by Holmes to deliver a box and a
            trunk at the union depot in this
            city. The box, according to Humph
            rey, was taken from a dark room
            and had the appearance of a coffin
            box. This was expressed to Phila
            delphia, while the trunk was sent
            in another direction.
            GHASTLY DETAILS.
            The story of the man who mount
            ed the skeletons is to the effect that
            in June, 1593, he was sent for by
            Holmes, who at that time was go
            ing under the alias of Gordon, and
            asked if he would articulate the
            skeleton of a man whose body was
            in the possession of Holmes. He ac
            cepted the job, and by the direction
            of Holmes he called at the house on ;
            a stipulated night. He was taken !
            by Holmes to a room which would
            have been dark even in the day
            time. Stretched out on a table in
            the middle of the room was the body
            of a man. The skin was entirely re
            moved from the face, but in all other
            respects it .*■ was in good condition.
            The articulator and Holmes had
            some talk as to the best way of get
            ting the body out of the house, as
            Holmes said he did not want the
            neighbors to see it removed. It was
            finally agreed that the articulator
            should cut off the, arms, and that
            Holmes would provide for the re- '
            moval of the rest of the ■. corpse, j
            This was done, and the articulator I
            left the house carrying the arms ;
            with him in a sack. He had just
            reached his house, and was prepar
            ing to go to bed, when ,he was
            called to the front door by a loud
            knocking. He went down and
            found Holmes and another man
            there. They had the balance of the
            body, which had been cut into two
            more pieces after, the articulator
            left the house. Holmes left, after !
            remarking that he would have an-
            VALKYRIE 111. ' '--•- DEFENDER; .r'*~ -.'..-* -. v» ■■'■■_ I
            other job for the man in a short
            time. True to his word, in Decem
            ber he sent for the articulator a sec
            ond time, and on the arrival of the
            latter at the house of Holmes he
            was taken to the same dark room,
            where en the same table where the
            body of a man had 'lain on the oc
            casion of his former visit, was the
            body of a young woman. The face
            of this corpse had been disfigured
            in such a manner that it was im
            possible to tell what she had looked
            like when alive. Y^YYY.Y
            The story of the expressman is to
            ST. PAUL, MINN., SUNDAY MORNING, JULY 28, 1895.---SIXTEEN PAGES.
            I the effect that he was hired by r
            Holmes one afternoon, and told not ;
            ito come to the house until after
            i nightfall. When the expressman
            ! kept his appointment he was given
            a box and a trunk by Holmes and i
            told to take them to the union depot. i
            When he was putting the box into
            the wagon he turned it on end, and i
            I was at once stopped by Holmes, who j
            told him that he was on no account i
            to keep the box in any other posi- I
            j tion except flat on the side. The or- i
            ders were to take the trunk and box I
            • to the depot and leave them on I
            the platform, and he was told that j
            they would be taken care of. He !
            saw only one man at the depot who
            seemed to be interested in the trunk I
            and the box. After Humphrey had
            told his story to the police tonight, j
            Pat Quinlan was brought up from j
            his cell and the two were placed
            face to face. The police will not j
            tell why this was done, but the
            general opinion is that it was done
            because Humphrey recognized Quin
            lan as the man at the depot. The
            expressman will be retained in cus
            ! tody as a witness.
            HIS THIRD TRIP.
            J In January, 1893, the articulator was
            I sent for a third time by Holmes, and in
            i the same room and on the same table
            j he found the body of a second young
            i woman, from whose face all the skin
            j had been removed. The articulator
            ! had this body taken to his home, where
            j he stopped the bones and mounted the
            i skelton. When he called on Holmes
            i for his pay the latter refused to give it
            i to him, and was, moreover, somewhat
            J in arrears on the bill for mounting the
            two previous skeltons. The two men
            could not come to terms and the dis
            pute finally ended by the articulator
            j retaining possession of the third skel
            ton, and he still has it it in his house.
            j He removed the skull tonight and
            brought it to the central police station,
            I where It now Is. The articulator will
            be kept under close surveillance for
            j some days yet, as the police do not
            I think that he has told them all he
            I knows about the murder in the "cas-
            I tie." He said at first that Holmes
            j called at his house under the name of
            i Gordon, and later said that he be
            j came acquainted with Holmes through I
            j answering an advertisement for a man j
            I capable In the work of articulating
            j skeletons, and found that the advertise-
            S ment had been inserted by Holmes,
            j Afterwards he let drop some expres
            , sions that showed that he had done
            j some work for Holmes prior to the time j
            ' that he claimed his acquaintance with
            i him began. This discrepancy in his
            j story decided the police to keep a close
            . watch on him. The police declare that
            ! they have almost positive proof that
            J the first female body was that of
            I Emeline Cigrand and the second that of
            Annie Williams. It is the skull of
            . Annie Williams that is now at the
            central police station.
            J BURIED IN QUICKLIME.
            In prosecuting the investigation of
            j the basement of the big brick house on
            j Sixty-third street today the workmen
            employed by the police came upon two
            graves. The indications are that in
            | the graves were laid the bodies of Mm
            J nic and Annie Williams. Lime and
            j quicklime had accomplished their work
            j and the bodies had turned to native |
            dust, but there still remained sufficient
            evidence to make the indentificati.on
            possible. Two soft spots in a bed of |
            hard clay were the size of human bod- j
            ies, and where the heads would have I
            been were mats of long hair. One big
            strand was of light color, like that of
            Annie, while the other was of the'
            brown hue of Minnie's hair. '
            The juxtaposition of the mats of
            hair would indicate that the bodies
            had been laid side by side, the heads
            but a few inches apart. Twelve men I
            worked with picks and shovels in the !
            I rear basement of the "castle" today. '
            ) They were divided into two squads, i
            j One squad worked under the the tin i
            j shop and the other attacked the dirt |
            j bottom of the. cellar, near the rear and I
            I west walls. It was clcse to the parti- .
            | tion between the rear and front cellars,
            j under the stairs leading from the tin (
            I shop, that early in the afternoon the j
            i two masses of quicklime were found.
            I Two bones and masses of hair were
            found in them. A long, wooden, shal- '
            j low vat was found two feet under the i
            ground. It was expected that when j
            cleared out evidences that a human I
            body had been buried there would be !
            found but the examination resulted
            i in nothing of the kind. Either it was
            a blind sewer or a secret repository.
            A LETTER TO PAT.
            The police have found a letter from
            . Holmes to Pat Quinlan, to which much
            importance is attached. The letter is
            j as follows:
            Dear Pat: Among ether fool theor
            ies, they think you took the Pietzel
            TO RACE FOR AMERICA'S CUP. *> *•" .
            boy to Michigan, and either left him
            there or put him out of the way. I
            have always told them that I never
            asked you to do anything illegal,- but
            they are bull-headed. Oct. 13 I saw
            you at the factory, I think. Can't
            you show where you were all the rest
            of the month? If they question you
            or threaten to arrest you, tell- them V
            anything there is -to tell about this or
            any other matters. They want to
            know if you were in Cincinnati or In
            Indianapolis about" Oct. 12. It 'is well
            for you to be able to know where you
            were -working. .1 am awfully sorry,
            Pat, for I have always tried to make
            things easy ; for you. . When . Minnie
            killed her sister I needed *- you - the
            worst way, but would not drag you t
            into it. If the detectives would go to
            New York, as I want them to, they :
            ! would find where Minnie W. took
            i them by boat. I have done no killing,
            ! Pat. One by one they are finding I
            ; them alive. Minnie W. will not come
            i here as long as there is any 'danger of
            her being arrested. A Boston man
            | knows where she is, and her guardian
            . (Mossie H. Watt) will go to her. Let I
            your* wife write me anything you I
            wish not oftener than two times a
            month, directing H. H. Holmes,
            County Prison, Tenth and Reed
            | streets Philadelphia, I cannot write
            l many letters to you. I am doing all I
            i can for all • Expect to hear shortly!
            fr m >* ou Give m y lQ ve to your wife i
            I and Cora. Tell her I have her picture
            &- l ?^'"E 1 ». wlth me and thank her
            i nnrt I- ell * he r I have a tame mouse
            f£2*i Spld r to kee P me company. jMy
            ! SS&y&TO orst part here - Clarence
            Phillips restaurant poor stuff would
            be fine compared with it. I only eat
            once a day. SMall be out of it sooner
            S" y° u expect. They kept Mrs. p.
            SSSS«* ix months when we
            S-JSS]*^ out on balL Made
            a fool of her - Write soon and free.
            Ask any questions you want to.
            C^eorgiana is visiting her mother.
            i «!3 t V "i? t two weeks ago. With re
            gard to all, H H H
            i v,.™ 6 ? 0 "* 1 Mem.)— lf. you see Tfedi, tell
            him I am much obliged to him.
            MURDER OF JULIA CONNOR.
            Asphyxiated, Cut Up and Cremat
            ed hy Holmes.
            CHICAGO, July 27.-Mrs. Patrick
            Quinlan lost her defiant spirit in the
            police inquisition. Two days' "sweat-
            DOX experience proved more than she
            £m I»v.beai;1 »v. beai ;. wit equanimity, and she
            told the police things which before had
            not been acknowledged. Chief of Po
            lice Badenoch said: Evidence secured
            from Mrs. Quinlan is highly important,
            fahe confessed to abetting Holmes in
            insurance swindles, and that is a step
            in the right direction. Patrick Quin
            lan, her husband, continues to protest
            he was a mere hireling, and roes not
            know Holmes' affairs at all. Mrs. Quin
            lan s evidence was that, after Mrs.
            Connor s disappearance it became nec
            essary for Holmes to produce her to
            collect some insurance. Mrs. Quinlan
            consented to act in her place. She
            went to the insurance office and swore
            she was Mrs. Connor, and signed that
            name. According to the statements of
            Jonathan Belmont it was Christmas
            night, four years and six months ago,
            that Mrs. Connor was killed.
            He believes she was asphyxiated in
            her room while she slept. Her room
            was a small one adjoining the dark
            ! bath room in the "castle." When all
            was still in the house Holmes switched
            on the gas. When the deed was ac
            complished Holmes stealthily admitted
            himself through- the secret door of the
            bath room, lifted the inanimate form
            ol Mrs. Connor from the bed, and car
            ried it to the bath room. Then, placing
            the body in the bath tub, he proceeded
            to cut It to pieces, and fed them to a
            hot fire in the stove. When all was
            done he took the ashes and parts of
            the body that had not been entirely
            burned and buried them in lime in the
            cellar. ■_._,.■..
            The police believe the chain of evi
            dence against Pat Quinlan now com
            plete, and Holmes' ex-janitor will be
            tried for murder here.
            A HISSING BROTHER.
            "Horace Williams Disappeared Be
            fore His Sisters Were Rilled.
            CHICAGO, July 27.— William Capps.
            the Fort Worth, Texas, attorney who
            is here in behalf of the heirs of the'
            Williams sisters, advanced a rather
            startling theory today, which if found
            to be true, will add another victim
            to the long list of murders already
            credited to Holmes. According- to
            Capps, Minnie R. Williams ' had a
            brother named Horace A. Williams in j
            Denver, Col. This young man either 1
            was killed or disappeared ' in May .or
            June, ISS3, shortly before the supposed
            murder of the Williams .sisters. The
            manner of his death iSjiiot known to
            the attorney, but he says he has ascer
            tained that the young man was insured '
            for $2,500 in favor of his sister Minnie.
            This fact Mr. Capps considers to be
            decidedly peculiar, as he says it is not
            reasonable to suppose Horace Williams
            would insure his life in favor of a sis
            ter who was already wealthy. He said
            that his Investigations upon this point
            were in an uncompleted state, but
            from what he had learned he was of the
            opinion that Holmes had first insured
            the young man and then been instru
            mental In causing his death.
            </text>
        </result>
      
        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014635/1895-08-03/ed-1/seq-1/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text> 
            FRESH STAET TAKEN
            HOLMES CASE SHOWS SYMPTOMS 0E
            A GEAND 0AYE-IN.
            Pat Oulnl.in and Ills Wlfo are Believed to
            have Turned States Kvidcncc on rrom
            Ise of Protection Confession In Writing
            Lawyer Humphrey of Tort Worth
            Yisits Allen and Says He Knows a Lot
            About Holmes Declares that 3Ifnn!e
            Williams Li, es Mediums Interview
            Enieline Cigrscd.
            Chicago, III., Aug. 2. The police have
            at last obtained a partial confession
            from Pat Quinlan, the janitor of the
            Holmes "castle" and have, they be
            lieve, positive evidence that Benjamin
            F. Pietzel was murdered in this city by
            Holmes and the corpse sent to Phila
            delphia. The confession was wormed out of
            Quinlan by means of a tip given the
            local officers by Detective Geyer of
            Philadelphia, who arrived in this city
            today. The exact nature of the story
            told by Quinlan the police will not re
            veal and in fact Chief Badenoch and
            Inspector Fitzpatrick have both denied
            that Quinlan or his wife made any con
            fession at all. Notwithstanding the
            denial of the police, however, it is posi
            tively known that Quinlan made a
            signed confession because it was left
            where Quinlan's signature on the docu
            ment could be seen, although the sub
            ject matter under which he wrote his
            name .could not be ascertained. Tonight
            however, it was learned that a confes
            sion was made covering all the detils
            of the murder of Pietzl with the ex
            ception of the actual place in which
            the crime was committed.
            This the police declare they will have
            tomorrow and they declare that by sun
            set of Aug. 5, they will have undisput
            able evidence that Pietzel came to his
            end through the direct agency of II. II.
            Holmes. The confession was obtained
            from the Quinlans only after the hard
            est kind of work, and at the price of a
            promise of immunity from punishment
            for all the part the Quinlan's may have
            borne in the murder of Pietzel or other
            crimes committed by Holmes.
            MINNIE WILLIAMS LIVES.
            Little Rock, Aug. 2. Attorney O. M.
            Humphreys of Fort Worth arrived here
            today and went almost imemdiately to
            the prison where he and Superintend
            ent McConnell were closeted for some
            time with Convinct Allen. Mr. Hum
            phreys represents the interests holding
            claims against Minnie Wiliam's prop
            erty in Fort Worth on debts contract
            ed by Holmes and his accomplices.
            After the conference he sead:
            "Undoubtedly Allen knows more than
            anybody else about the transfer of the
            Williams property because he spoke to
            me intelligently about the various pa
            pers conected with the deal which are
            now In my possession and the contents
            of which have never been made public.
            I knew Allen in Fort Worth and from
            circumstances as yet unpublished which
            he mentioned to me today, in connec
            tion with those deals. I know he was
            intimate with Holme"."
            "Do you think Minnie Williams is
            still alive?"
            "I most assuredly do. From what I
            know and from what Allen said today,
            I am positive that she is not only liv
            ing but that she is in the United States
            and that were Holmes free he would be
            with her in less than forty-eight hours."
            WHAT MRS. QUINLAN KNOWS.
            Mrs. Pat Quinlan knew of the disap
            pearance of Mrs. Julia L. Conner in
            Holmes' castle and saw the body of
            the woman after she was elead. She
            further knew and has admitted that
            Pearl Conner disappeared mysterious
            ly in the castle after her return from
            a trip to the Quinlan farm at Lake
            Michigan.
            Chief Badenoch took Mrs. Quinlan
            and her husband to the castle today
            with Inspector Fitzpatrick and detec
            tives Fitzpatrick and Norton. The ob
            ject of this trip was more for the pur
            pose of letting Quinlan and his wife
            meet than any other. They were clos
            eted together alone for an hour in the
            room in which the Julia Conner's car
            pet lies and the chair belonging to the
            murdered woman stands. What took
            place between them no one knows but
            Chief Badenoch and his detectives. The
            chief now has proof positive that Mrs.
            Connor and Pearl, her daughter, or Co
            ra Quinlan, were murdered in the main
            building while the mother was in
            Holmes' employe. Quinlan has given
            information within the last twenty-four
            hours which brings the charge of mur
            der nearer to Holmes than it has been
            in Chicago at any time since the case
            opened. Quinlan and his wife while
            demonstrating to the police that they
            were at no time guilty of the crime of
            murder themselves have made admis
            sions by which the chief could use
            them on the stand as valuable witness
            es against Holmes in proving that Mrs.
            Conner anil a child were made away
            with by Holmes for the purpose of se
            curing insurance which Mrs. Cononr
            carried on her life in favor of her
            daughter or in which Cora Quinlan
            cut an important figure.
            Further, Quinlan and his wife have
            proved to the police that Mrs. Con
            nor was so Avell aware of the schemes
            which Holmes were operating that it
            became necessary for Holmes to put
            the woman out of the way.
            Mrs. Connor's bo lv was disposed of
            by burial within tne castle somewhere
            close to tfie spot where Pearl's sup
            posed body was found. The police have
            not ceased their effort" to flnd the bot
            tom of the basement and uncover her
            remains. The digging which was sus
            pended today will continue tomorrow
            and during the coming week. Pat Quin
            Ian and his wife have admitted parti
            ally, the woman more than the man.
            that a business in receiving and dis
            posing of dead bodies stolen from
            country graveyards was carried on in
            the castle under tli direction of
            Holmes. The graveyards of the west
            ern portion of Michigan. Grand Haven
            South Haven. Muskeg.-.n.. Holland. St.
            Joseph. The Bay. Laka. all ancient
            places, with venerable graves were de-sp-Mled
            of bodies.
            The bodies were brought to the cas
            tle, chemically treated ani thn dis
            posed of to medfeal colleges The cof
            fins were re-made by Quinlan. Pietael
            and Holmes, reliaed and disposed of to
            undertakers at a fair profit.
            We have suOlcSent evidence to keep
            Holmes In prion for t he remainder of t
            his natural days" said Detective Geyer
            toiay. "wicnout cnarjnng- nim with
            murder. Should he. by technicalitv.
            escape the conspiracy charge in Phila
            delphia, twenty worrants oa other char
            ges are ready to 'be served on hca. The
            Toronto charge of murder is the stron
            gest one acalnst hira and if he is tak
            en there he will probably be hanged
            As to all the Chicago charges there is
            only proof that he was a swindler. I
            believe it will be finally shown that
            he did murder Mrs. Conner and the
            two Williams girls. M'nnie Williams
            J think, was killed last fall at the same
            time as Howard Pletsel."
            EXPRESSMAN'S STORY.
            .cw witneses in tne rioime case
            ... . amm lilM tAd T....T-. ji. .. . " .. . ?
            i.uc uw -;- -i: rs.ir.ianj- ,
            son. tne expressaian. ar.i.-d a back
            up the testimony of M O thar-o-11.
            Holmes' "bone rigger" h . n t d--.t
            as reported. (
            Richardson corroborates Chappeirs
            story. He fcas told the police all he
            knows oi noimes .ramc in mysterious
            packages ana ooxes ana Debtees the
            express companies receipt? in the Wash
            ir.gtoa street office show just how much
            work Holmes had done is. the years I
            1S91-93 and where the "packages" he
            handled were delivered.
            The new witness said he did not
            know what these packages contained
            at the time they were handled. To the
            police he made no reservations but
            since Chappell says his traffic was in
            dead men's bones Richardson says he
            is quite prepared to believe it. The num
            ber of these trips to the Wallace street
            house he adds cannot be contained In
            twenty calls, nor thirty.
            "X remember this special package
            very well," said Richardson. "Holmes
            sent these boxes all over the city at
            times to physicians and medical stu
            dents and again to the hospitals direct
            A good part of the stuff was also taken
            to the various depots. He received a
            good many consignments himsplf from
            other points. The boxes handled as I
            remember them were strong and ticht
            C-nd there were also well headed barrels
            in numbers. I don't remember of see
            ing that old trunk Chappell turned up
            r.or do I recall any trips to dump stuff
            in the lake. I guess Holmes had use
            for most everything he handled with
            out throwing anything away."
            MEMPHIS KICKS ON ALLEN.
            Memphis, Tenn., Aug. 2. The Little
            Rock end of the Holmes murder sen
            sation is about petered out. In the next
            forty-eight hours the police will in all
            probability, have proen tha Convict
            John Caldwell could have had no con
            nection with Holmes and his crimes, as
            he was in the Tennessee penitentiary
            for horse stealing at the time he claims
            to have been operating in Fort Worth
            Tex., for Holmes. A few months ago
            he was pordoned but went Immediate
            ly to Arkansas and engnged in his for
            mer pursuit. There he again came to
            grief and was sent to the Arkansas
            state prison where he now is. The
            Memphis police are confident Caldwell's
            story is only a ruse to get out of prison.
            WANTS PAY FOR TALK.
            Minneapolis, Minn., Aug. 2. "Two
            hundred dollars, sir." is the cash value
            placed by C. W. Arnold, the insurance
            agent, on his knowledge of the career
            of Holmes. Nevertheless for the last
            two days Arnold has been a constant at
            tendant at the newspaper offices here
            and has been interviewed to his heart's
            content.
            Arnold was asked point blank today
            as to his holding shares in the com
            panies organized by Holmes for vari
            ous purposes. If you like to pay me
            $200 I will write out what I know and
            hand It to you and the Minneapolis pa
            pers shall publish it at the same time.
            I will dictate it myself to a stenograph
            er, but I tell you before hand I do not
            think it worth a cent to you, as I had
            no knowledge of any crimes. Holmes
            used my name In those companies with
            out my knowledge or authority. In the
            same breath he added: "I never invest
            ed a cent in any of his companies and
            certainly had no knowledge of any of
            his swindling operations. I never went
            up stairs in the house or building. I
            never saw a stenographer or typewriter
            there. There was no handsome blonde
            typewriter there so far as I saw. I
            knew nothing of his vats or furnaces. I
            never sats them. I never saw, met, or
            knew Kmlllne Cigrand, Mrs. Connor,
            or her daughter, Mrs. Lee, Minle Will
            iams or her sister, nor Emily von Tas
            sel. I never insured any of those peo
            ple for Holmes or at Holmes sugges
            tion. All I can say is as to my person
            al dealings with and friendship for Mr.
            Holmes, and I am out for the stuff and
            intend to get it before I say anything.
            Two hundred dollars Is my price. You
            put up the money and I will write you
            a story of a dozen of extraordinary
            facts about Holmes, but I won't talk
            to reporters I am busyv There Is a
            good market for this kind of stuff. Why
            several novelists have already approac
            hed me and offered me large sums to
            tell what I know of Holmes for publi
            cation in book form. I am wanting the
            money and can use it In my business,
            nnd I shall not talk, I tell you, until I
            get it."
            Then Mr. Arnold, who had done most
            of the talking, waited for questions
            with the sang froid of an experienced
            politician. He was atked as to insur
            ances effected by him for Holmes or at
            Holmes' instigation and claimed that
            he insured Holmes by three separate
            policies for $5,000 each, which policies
            Holmes neglected to pay for or take up.
            Arnold admits insuring Pietzel for 2000
            but claims that this policy lapsed and
            long before Pietzel met his end. When
            asked for particulars as to insurance
            companies for whom he worked in Chi
            cago, Arnold denied positively having
            worked for the Mutual Life of Philadel
            phia, the Northwestern or the Vermont
            and in the same breath refused to say
            what companies he worked for.
            When questioned closely as to his
            dealingswith Holmes he claimed that
            his acquaintance was purely a passing
            friendship, though he might have act
            ed as witness to various legal docu
            ments. As to the nature of these he
            essayed to be very mysterious and he
            point blank asked for pecuniary com
            pensation for divulging. He absolute
            ly denies that he was out from 11 p m.
            until 3 a. m. on any occasion attting
            legal documents for Holmes ar. I cut
            short the conversation bv sa ing be
            would talk no more until S200 was forth
            coming for his information.
            SPIRITS ARE INVOKED.
            Anderson, Ind., Aug. 2. The friends
            of Mr. and Mrs. Peter Cigrand, whose
            daughter Emeline is believed to have
            been one of H. H. Holmes' victims, are
            much interested in the attempt by
            spiritualist seances to communicate
            with the spirit of Emeline. A number
            of people have had private sittings with
            mediums, but a they report no satis
            faction a woman whose name must be
            withheld went into a seance for the
            spirit of EmeJine.
            After sitting in a dark room for near
            ly two hours she ays there was a voice
            in the trumpet and she understood it to
            say:
            "This is Emma. I went into the spirit
            land two years ago and was far from
            home. O, it was so horrible." Here the
            words became whispers and were not
            audible. Suddenly another voice said:
            "I hope sister will soon join me. I
            have something awful to tell her. My
            husband is stil beyond the spirit land.
            I send love to mamma and papa, and
            tell the to " and here the spirit stop-
            ped and could not be called again.
            Mrs. Bibbeth Seery. one of the best
            of Indiana mediums, was sen at her
            home in Muncie tonight. Sho would
            not attempt to call up the spirit of
            Emeline Cigrand, for she said it was
            absurd.
            "The laws of aature are the govern
            ment r all mediums and spirit." said
            the medium. "The dead girl would have
            to be well known to any one speaking (
            who saould have talked with the girl
            in worldly life shortly before death. I
            Natural resources are arainst nie. for I
            saould one spirit be called and told to
            hont for the spirit of the girl it would
            not know the spirit. Should she- call !
            circumstances attending her death a
            reported it would affect the spiritual
            condition "
            A trance medium attempted to talk
            with the girl's spirit. He asuaied a
            trance state and speaking for a spirit
            EAld- ,
            "All seems dark; ao Hgnt asywhre: j
            come, come quick: I eaanot be here
            locg. O, had I known this. J
            Here the medium came out of the !
            trance. He promised to make aaother j
            effort,
            The nv-ifSr nf t'b.a fMsrranri f-lrl eoM I
            jae cei eveo some of tae sptntF talking
            ver those of her dausrher. aad will I
            a:-' sd a aeaace as soon as one can be
            arranp-d for ar. ,
            TMav Kansas relatives of Emeline J
            Cigrand wroe to ask how ?he and hr
            husband. Phlos were getting along !
            Thy kn-w not of her disappearance.
            Sirs. Henderson of IndUnapoHs haF
            been called home bv detectives who
            want her evidence about Holmes while
            he was a.; Indlsxapolia,</text>
        </result>

        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024441/1895-10-28/ed-1/seq-1/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
                                    Churlcs Heed Sbnotx In tlie Presence
              of Wife and Sinter.
              Ban Francisco. Oct. 28. Charles Eeed
              committed suicide at Point Bonlta yes
              terday In .a most peculiar manner.
              TVith his wife and sLster-in-law, he drove
              out to Point fionlla and spent some time
              fishing.
              Willie the ladles were about to depart
              for the buggy on the return trip, they weye
              horrified to see Reed step out on a high
              rock, draw his revolver, place It to his
              forehead, fire and fall Into the water. His
              body has not been recovered.
              He appeared to be in good health and
              spirits, and ixf eaimeTor his act can be as
              signed. w(
              Acetylene Csas onr exhibition, day and
              evening, at 81 17th Blreet nortlim&t.
              BeKlnnlugnt tho Case of the Man Who,
              if All Thut'lM Sunpectod Bo True,
              Will Bo Found to Bo tho Most Hor
              rible Impostor mid All-Hound Crim
              inal of Modern TimeM.
              Philadelphia, Pa., Oct. 28. Herman W.
              Mudgett, better known as H.U.Molmes,
              the seir-confessed life insurance swindler
              anil the alleged multi-murderer, whose sup
              posed crimes ha e been a topic Tor general
              Uscusslon during the past .several months,
              was placed on trial this morning in the
              court or oyer and terminer on the charge
              or having murdered Benjamin F. Pltezei.
              Judge Arnold presided. -
              Tlie Commonwealth was represented by
              District Attorney George S. Graham and
              Assistant District Attorney Thomas W.
              Barlow and the defense was conducted by
              V. U. Shoemaker and Samuel P. Rotau.
              lu audition to the uurder or Pllezcl. the
              prisoner is also accused or the murder, at
              Toronto, Onl., of Fltczel's two young
              daughters, Alice and Nellie; of the murder,
              at Irviugton, Ind., ot the yoaug son, How
              ard Pltezei, and also of the murder of
              various other persons In the famous Holmes
              elastic at Chicago.
              STORY OP THH ARREST.
              Benjamin F. Piterel's liody was round In
              a house at 131C Callow hill street 011 Sep
              tember 3, 1894. A shattered lamp was
              found by the side of -the body wliUh bore
              evidence of having iie-en turned, and the
              coroner's Jury concluded ttiat tlie oil lamp
              had exploded and that Pilczcl, who was
              at the time known as M. F. Perry, had been
              burned to deutti. and accordingly rendered
              a vcntUt or accidental death.
              There was no claimant ror the body and
              it was buried in Potter's field. Subse
              quently an assertion came iroin Mrs. Fltc
              zel's lawyer at St. Louis, Mr. Jeplha
              Uowe, that the body w.u that of Benjamin
              F. Pltezei, and a claim was made ou the
              Fidelity Mutual Life Association of Phil
              adelphia for $10,000, which that cotu
              pauy carries! on Pitezel's life.
              Tlie insurance company paid the claim,
              but not Is'iiig satisfied tti.it Pllc-zel had
              niet his el am accidentally, at once placed
              delective3 on the case to solve the mys
              tery. This rcsu'ltesl in tlie arrest in Bos
              ton or Mudgett, alias Holmes.
              The lane, was opu.uc. lure and vas
              placed 011 trial charged with conspiracy to
              defraud the insurance company. Holmes
              pleaded guilty to Ihjs charge, but to cum
              bat tlie more serious ciiarge of inurdtr
              claimed that Pilczcl is still litiiig: that a
              body was ohtaine-d from a Ner Vork dls
              sesting room arsljilactsl in the building on
              Callowhili strct. alter burning the skin
              sllghtlv and throning a lamp 011 the floor.
              Holmes (laiincd that he .mil Pltezei lelt
              the city and suhseeiui ntly informed Mrs.
              Pitezel that the body was that or her
              missing husband and had her press her
              claim for the insurance.
              GKYKU'S DISCOVERIES.
              Holmes was sent to prison to await sen
              tence on tlie conspiracy trial, anil District
              Attorney Graham startesl Ilctcctlte Gcyer
              out to v lslt Toronto, Chicago and other
              Western cities, to endeavor to obtain ci
              dence against Holmes which would warrant
              his being arruigucs! for murder.
              Deles tle Geyer's sucoc-s In rinding the
              dead bodies or Ihe children Is well I. noun,
              and otlur rails which he gleanesl sallsricd
              District Attorney Graham that Holmes could
              be comlcied here o.the murder of Pltezei.
              Detective GPyer also brought to this city
              Mrs. Pltezei anil others from various parts
              or tlie Wist and Canada lo take the stand
              as wltnisssMS against Holmes.
              The approaches to the court room were
              closely guarded, and Hone but jicrsons di
              rectly intcre-sted in the caso.and newspaper
              men, were admitted. The case was called
              shortly after 10 o'clock.
              Holmes walked Jauntily into tlie dock,
              a tipstaff being on cither side of him. He
              was rather pale from long conrincment in
              tlie county prison, but his black beard was
              neatly trimmed, and his black suit of
              clothing gave him adressy appearance.
              Tlie accused took his sent with a calmness
              that was noticeable, and whlleheetlnceda
              decided interest in the matters at issue,
              there was no look of fear upon Ms counto
              nance nor any evidence of nervousness in
              his action.
              SENSATIONAL EPISODE.
              , Judge Arnold overruled the motions for
              postponement in a very few words, and
              ordered the trial to go on. Just at this
              Juncture a startling climax was reached,
              which resulted in the withdrawal of Law
              yers Shoemaker and Rotan from the case,
              notwithstanding an injunction from tho
              court that they would be open to disbar
              ment by taking such a step "ou the eveof a
              murder trial."
              Stili further sensation was created wiien
              Holmes refused to accept the services of
              Attorney! Everett A. Sehofield and Joseph.
              R. Fahy, whom the court was about to ap
              point to -defend him and who, lu fact, had
              taken "scats in the hairs vacated by Messrs.
              Shoemaker and Rotan.
              Sehorieldaud Fahy also withdrew. Holmes
              himself pleaded to the court for a post
              ponement, but the Judge declared that
              tho case must go on. The trial was re
              sumed, Holmes conducting his own defense.
              DESTRUCTIVE OIL FIRES.
              They Sweep Miles of tbo Best Ohio
              Petroleum Territory.
              Toledo, Ohio, Oct. 28. Ever since Sat
              urday night a desperate fire has been raging
              in the coal regions south of here.
              The telegraph and telephone lines arc
              nearly all rendered useless in that Immedi
              ate vicinity, and detailed reports of the
              damage have been difficult to secure.
              The fire seems to have done most damage
              about Merndl, Cygnet and Lucky. Among
              the heaviest losers are the Sun 011 Company,
              nine derricks, four tanks and a boiler
              house, the Palmer Oil Company, twelveder
              rlcks, several tanks and other property;
              the Ohio Oil Company, four derricks and
              other property. Half Brothers, several der
              ricks and buildings.
              The fire startesl on Hie edge of the town
              of Vungen, and burnesl two miles to the
              northeast, a strip nearly a mile wide, de
              stroying everything. This is the heart of
              the best producing oil territory in Ohio.
              The fire is now practically under con
              trol, and while the loss ivlll be very heavy
              from reports at hand, an accurate estimate
              cannot be given. One estimate is $1C0,
              000, others higher.
              After JaeKsion's llolo Murderer.
              Rawlins, Wyo., Oct. 28. The .United
              States marshal for Wyoming Is ntJack
              son's Hole for the purpose of arresting set
              tlers who comprlsearthe constable's posse,
              which, in July last, killed and wounded sev
              eral Indians and precipitated Ihe Bannock
              scare.
              Quiet in Venezuela.
              New York, Oct. 28. Passengers on the
              steamer Caracas, from La Quayrn, Porto
              Cabello, and Curacao, report all quiet. in
              Venezuela when they left. Business was
              good and there, was no excitement what
              ever. It was felt tliat the boundary question
              would be settled without-troubles-
              Tlie executive committee jftheUulverslty
              ofVlrgiuiaaiumulherewnaieetat4oV.2otk
              this afternoon at the oitlcjeof Chairman
              Cazenove G. Lee, No. 1405P street north
              west, to determine what car) be done to hclp
              their aimer mater in thi great misfortune
              that has overtaken her.'
              Prof. Wm. 11. Cabell, of Norwood Insti
              tute, at once upon learning of the fire at
              Charlottesville sat clowp jund wrote letters
              to Dr. Win. M. Thornton, cbancelloror the
              university, and to W.C.N! Randolph. rector
              or the I ward of v isltors, suggesting the plan
              of having all the alumul associations lu the
              country co-operate to restore the loss of
              y csterday.
              Prol. Caliell resirgariucd the universlty
              aliimm here in 1888, unci was continuously
              president till the selccjlon of Secretary
              Herbert ror that place, at tbcaonuat meet
              ing last April. Mr. Cupell was made a
              vice president. His susgestton at once
              met the approval or Ihej.ocal sochty, and
              the meeting or the executive snnmltlee at
              Chairman Lee's office was called.
              The association here numbers about ISO
              member, including Postmaster General
              Wilson, Senators Daniel and Faulkner,
              Solicitor Holmes Conrad, Assistant Secre
              tary C. W. Daluiey, Thomas Nelson Page,
              I'ruf. Montague and other men. of nigf
              rank. 1
              Besides Prof. Cabell, toe vice presidents
              are Postmaster General Wilson, E. T,
              Reulck. L. W. Blackford, and Dr. G. 11.
              Harrison. E. P.. McClelland Is srerctary
              and Dr. L. W. Glazchrorfk, treasurer.
              The executive committee-, which meets
              this afternoon, consists of Chairman Lee,
              Thomas Nelson Page, R. L. Preston.
              Clare-nee Thomas and Dr. Taliaferro Clark.
              They hate already on band sonic funds
              started by a $100 contribution by Dr.
              Page for a Confederatcltuemorial to the
              alumni who fell in the civil war. This may
              lie turned to account f or pressing needs now
              to be replaces! later. .
              Beside the committee, It Is expect isl that
              officers and some of thivleadiug members
              will ls at the meeting.
              There are alumul associations, in New
              York, Baltimore, St. Louis. San Fran
              cisco, Louis lie, Nahvllle. New Orleans,
              Memphis, Kansas City, Charleston. W.
              Va., and sixteen other places in the coun
              try. It is expected all will respond
              promptly to the need of help on the part
              of Ibis old and honoredinstltutlon, which
              has bee-n the pride of the Stale since It was
              started by Jefferson In IfilOj  
                      
                      
                      
                      </text>
        </result>

        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1896-05-08/ed-1/seq-1/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
                            HANGED FOR
              MANY CRIMES,
              Murderer Holmes' Career
              Comes to an End on
              the Gallows.
              STUBBORN TO THE LAST
              He Died as if Entirely In
              different to His Awiul
              Fate.
              DECLARING HIS INNOCENCE.
              The Execution Passed Off Without
              Any Incidents of a Sensa
              tional Nature.
              PHILADELPHIA, Pa., May 7.—Her
              man W. Mudgett, alias H. H. Holmes,
              was hanged this" mornine in the County
              Prison for tne killing of Benjamin F.
              Pietzel.
              The drop fellatlO:l2o'cloctc, and twenty
              minutes later he was pronounced dead by
              the prison officials, Dr. Sharp and Dr.
              Batcher.
              The execntion was in every way entirely
              devoid of any sensational features.
              To the last Holmes was self-possessed
              and cool, even to the extent of giving a
              word of advice to Assistant Superintend
              ent Richardson as the latter -was arrang
              ing the final details. He died as ne had
              lived, unconcerned and thoughtless, ap
              parently, of the future, even with the rec
              ollection still vividly before him of the
              H. H. Holmes, alias Mudgett, the Arch Criminal of Modern History. Who Was
              Hanged Yesterday.
              recent confession in which he admitted
              the killing of a score of persons of both
              sexes in different parts of the country.
              Almost his last words were a point-blank
              denial of any crimes committed except the
              deaths of two women at his hands by mal
              practice.
              Of the murder of several members of tbe
              Pietzel family he denied all complicity,
              particularly of the father, for whose death
              he stated he was unjustly suffering the
              penalty. With the prayer of the spiritual
              attendants still sounding in his ears and
              with a few low-spoken words to those
              about him tbe trap was sprang.
              There were comparatively few persons
              gathered on the outside of the prison dur
              ing the eariy part of the morning and the
              morbid throng which the prison officials
              expected would be drawn there by the
              execution was lacking. Access to the
              prison prior to the entrance of those per
              mitted to witness the execution was not
              allowed.
              All the arrangements for the burial of
              Holmes were entrusted by the murderer
              to Mr. Rotan. The place of interment has,
              it is understood, been selected, but those
              who are most likely to know where the
              grave is to be will not divulge the iov-a
              tion.
              Holmes retired about midnight and
              slept soundly during the entire time until
              called at 6 o'clock this morning. So sound
              were his slumbers, in fact, that twice was
              he called before awauening. When the
              arrival of the Rev. Fathers Dailey and Me-
              Pake to administer the sacrament was an
              nounced he greeted them warmly, but
              witii no show of emotion. For nearly two
              hours they remained in the cell and then
              were succeeded by Lawyer Rotan, the le
              gal adviser of Holmes, who was also
              greeted pleasantly. There were several
              matters pertaining to Holmes' worldly af
              fairs that will yet have to be settled and
              this time was taken in giving the final de
              tails and explanations. While discussing
              his affairs breakfast was served, consisting
              of eggs, toast and coffee.
              When the raeal was ended, shortly be
              fore 9 o'clock, Holmes dressed himself in
              trousers, vest and cutaway coat of some
              dark mixed goods of a pepper and salt ef
              fect he aad worn frequently.
              At 10 o'clocK the doors leading to the
              long corridor in which was placed the
              gallows were opened and, two by two, led
              by the Sheriff's jury, the spectators
              passea down. The last man had just
              passed through the doors and the latter
              closed when from behind was heard the
              slow and measured tread of the death
              party.
              The suspense was almost painful, brief
              though it was, when, preceded by Sheriff
              Clements and Superintendent Perkins,
              Holmes appeared and stepped on the trap.
              On the right was Father Dailey, to the
              left Fat; er McPake, and behind them
              Lawyer Rotan and Assistant Superin
              tendent Richardson. The little party
              stood a moment looking down, and then,
              in response to a signal from one of those
              beside him, Holmes stepped forward. He
              spoke slowly and with measured attention
              to every word— a trifle low at first, but
              louder as he proceeded, until every woid
              was distinctly audible.
              "Gentlemen," he said, "I have very few
              words to say, in fact, I would make no
              statemeut at this time, except that by not
              speaking I may be made to acquiesce in
              my execution. I only want to say that
              the extent of my wrongdoings in the
              taking of human life consisted in the
              death of two women, they having died at
              my hands as the result of criminal opera
              tions. I wish to state also, however, so that
              there will be no misunderstanding here
              after, tnat I am not guilty of taking the
              lives of any of the Pietzel family, the three
              children or the father, Benjamin F. Piet
              zel, of whose death I am now convicted,
              and for which I am to-day to be hanged.
              That is all."
              As he ceased speaking he stepped back,
              and kneeling between Fathers Dailey and
              McPake, he joined with them in silent
              prayer for a minute or two. Again stand
              ing he sbook hands with all about him
              and then signified his readiness for the
              end. Holmes was the coolest of the wuole
              yiarty. He even went to the extreme of
              suggesting to Assistant Superintendent
              Richardson that the latter should not
              hurry himself.
              "Take your time; don't bungle it,"
              Holmes remarked as the official exhibited
              some little haste, the outcome of nervous
              ness. These were almost his last words.
              The cap was adjusted, a low-toned query,
              "Are you ready?" and an equally low
              toned response, "Yes, good-by," and the
              trap was sprung.
              Holmes' neck was not broken, and there
              were a few convulsive twitches of the
              limbs that continued for about ten min
              utes. "But he suffered none after the
              drop," said Dr. Scott, the prison physi
              cian.
              The trap was sprung precisely at ]0:12)£,
              and fifteen minutes later Holmes was pro
              nounced dead, though the body was not
              cut down until 10:45. When ii was laid
              out on the stretcher occurred the only in
              cident approaching the revolting in con
              nection with the affair.
              The knot bad become jammed and the
              efforts of the doctors failed to loosen it as
              they attempted to remove the noose from
              about the neck. The head was twisted
              about from side to side in the attempt, and
              finally it was decided to cut the rope.
              Superintendent Perkins objected, however,
              and the knot was undone after several
              minutes of trying work.
              After the body had been viewed by the
              physicians and the manner of death dt
              termined the stretcher on whicn it lay was
              wheeled out of the corridor into the jail
              yard. Hero it was placed in an ordinary
              cheap pine coffin, wide enough and deep
              enough to have held two men of Holmes'
              size. The coffin was put aboard an under
              taker's wagon and conveyed to the Roman
              Catholic Cemetery of the Holy Cross.
              The only persons at the cemetery were
              the undertaker and his assistant, two
              grave-diggers, two watchmen and a couple
              of newspaper men. The little company
              acted as pallbearers, and carried the coffin
              to the receiving vault. The last act in tne
              receiving vault was performed at Holmes'
              express command.
              The lid of the coffin was taken off and
              the body was lifted out and laid on the
              ground. Then the bottom of tbe coffin
              was filled with cement. The body was
              then replaced in the coffin and covered
              with cement. It was Holmes' idea that
              this cement would harden around his
              body and prevent any attempt at grave
              robbery. The coffin was left in the receiv
              ing vault under the guard of two watch
              men, who will remain on duty all night.
              To-morrow afternoon the body will be in
              terred in a grave in the cemetery, and it is
              probable that at the time religious serv
              ices will be conducted by Father Dailey.
              Holmes made no will and left no con
              fession. This is according to Mr. Rotan.
              He says he knows Holmes made no will,
              and, while the murderer gave him this
              mornine a big bundle of papers, the law
              yer says that he is confident that these
              papers relate only to private business
              matters. A3 yet Mr. Rotan has had no
              opportunity to examine them.
              Mrs, Pietzel was seen after Holmes was
              hanged. All she could say, between her
              sobs, was that she was glad that he had
              received her just deserts, but that his
              death would not return to her her hus
              band or her children. Mrs. Pietzel will
              return to her home, at Galva, 111., next
              week.
              The two women referred to by Holmes
              in nis confession from the scaffold were
              Julia Connor of Chicago and Emily
              Cigrand of Anderson, Ind.
              HOLMES' MANY CRIMES.
              He Had a Ready "Confession" to Clear
              Himself of Ench.
              Herman W. Mudgett, better known as
              H. H. Holmes, was one of the most con
              spicuous criminals of modern times, and
              If the "murder confessions" which he has
              written can only partially be believed, he
              was without a peer as a bloodthirsty
              demon. His recent ingenious "confes
              sion," wherein he claimed to have killed
              twenty-seven persons, was disproved,
              partly, at least, by the appearance of sev
              eral of the so-called victims: but Holmes'
              object in making the "confession" was re
              alized — the obtaining of a sum said to be
              $7500 and which amount is said to have
              been settled upon the criminal's 18-year
              old son. While the "confessions" have
              served to increase the sensationalism of
              the case, the only capital crime for which
              Holmes had to answer was the killing in
              this city on September 2, 1884, of Benja
              min F. Pietzel, bis fellow-conspirator.
              The murder was committed in the dwell
              ing, 1316 Callowhill street. Holmes' con
              viction of murder in the first degree, the
              affirmation by the Pennsylvania Supreme
              Court of the verdict and the recent re
              fusal of Governor Hastings to grant a re
              spite, are so well known that a narration
              oJ these facts is unnecessary.
              Holmes was captured in Boston, Mass.,
              in the latter part of 1894 by Owen Hans
              com. the Deputy Superintendent of
              upon the strength of a telegram from Fort
              Worth, Tex., where he was wanted for
              Continued on Second Page
                      
          
          
          
          
          </text>
        </result>

        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn98066406/1914-03-12/ed-1/seq-6/ocr/</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
          <text>CRIME CASTLE GUILDER DEAD
            Portland Carpenter Takes Poison Be
            cause He Couldn't Sleep.
            Portland, Mich. Patrick Quinlan.
            who was said to be one of the. few men
            who might have explained the myste
            ries of "Holmes' Crime Castle,' 'which
            was famous in the annals of Chicago
            crime, Is dead at his home near here.
            Before his death he told physicians
            ho had taken poison.
            Quinlan was a carpenter and was
            employed by Dr. J. J. Holmes to
            build the structure. The police held
            him for a time as a possible accom
            plice. Trap-doors, false partitions and
            numbers of wires were part of the
            equipment found'ln the "Castle".
            "He couldn't sleep" was the reason
            given by relatives for Quintan's sui
            cide.
            MAY NOT HAVE CUILDING.</text>
        </result>


        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85058396/1914-07-04/ed-1/seq-19/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text>
                          A few weeks ago word was sent
              over the telegraphic wires that Pat
              rick Qulnlan had killed himself In
              his home at Portland. Mich. The
              I telegram did not cause much of a
              llr. Quintan's name had been for
              gotten. A new generation Is read
              ing the newspapers, which nineteen
              years ago carried stories da.y after
              day for month about the remark
              ,i able murder system of H. H,
              Holmes, with whose name the name
              of Qulnlan was linked.
              I Quinlan proved his Innocence. He
              howed that he was only an em
              ploye of H. H. Holmes, arch-murderer.
              He proved that he was
              Holmes' Janitor and caretaker of the
              Holmes Castle. 701 Sixty-third
              street, Chicago, and nothing more
              Tt, He admitted he had helped con-
              lt;iD,e . struct some of the secret trap doors
              st it . mnj helped lino some of the
              exist rooms with asbestos, which it Is be-
              Ths lleved aided in deadening the sound
              and Cf dying men, but Qulnlan knew
              nothing of the purpose of the traps
              ufn- he helped to build, and had no part
              flea In the machinations of his chief.
              W Yet when the body of Quinlan was
              fleas. found lying in his room whero he
              thou- I had taken poison, a note was found
              .lump beside his body. Tho note said:
              from "I could not sleep."
              thing For nineteen years Qulnlan could
              can- not sleep. At night he would wake
              ac- i with x start, and find himself cov
              d tho red with sweat, his friends say. He
              :ther. i would call for help and when a light
              care would be brought to his room or
              is aS when the electric switch would be
              turned on he would recount how he
              .ml- '-I was attacked while half asleep by
              The fctrange hallucinations,
              r dis- I For nineteen years this man had
              pirlcr. ''been unable to sleep peacefully be-
              e -pi- cause of the awful experiences ho
              gs to 3 ndured during his employment by
              earestj Holmes and during the period im--linant
              mediately after.
              times. Holmes Castle was a three-story
              is and I flat, looking more like an ordinary
              d the f residence than like a castle. In that
              place it Is believed four women, at
              lpn- I least, were slain. It was the retreat
              If to " f the man who also had killed men
              jp iv I 'women and children In Philadelphia,
              r pro- ! Toronto and Indianapolis.
              , d un-" Tne castle was built admirably for
              iea it's a murdef shop. A dumb waiter ran
              for from the third floor to the basement
              are nfl there were no connections with
              t long ne dumD waiter on the intervening
              eill floors. The conveyance was big
              enough to admit of a man riding
              k Upon it, On the top floor In one of
              the rooms was ligantiC BtOVfe It
              m c sr alKht feet high and three feet
              r wer
              house.
              in diameter. It was an ideal stove
              for tho burning of a human body.
              A person could be thrown into the
              stove bodily and could be burned to
              nothing.
              In tho basement were quicklime
              vats. Bodies could be thrown in
              quicklime and consumed. The flag
              ging in the basement could be torn
              up and bodies could bo buried be
              neath the flags.
              The trouble with the average sla
              er Is that he does not know what to
              do with the body of hLs victim.
              FINDING OF BODY
              STARTS SEARCH.
              The finding of the body of a vic
              tim always starts the search for the
              slayer. If a man could dispose of
              tho body he could slay on a whole
              sale plan and avoid detection.
              Holmes is believed to have built the
              castle with a view of hiding bodies
              of those he slew. He directed the
              work on the building. Qulnlan was
              only an ordinary workman who did
              what he was told unhesitatingly.
              Qulnlan never questioned the au
              thority of the slayer. He never
              asked who the women were Holmes
              had visiting him. He never asked
              where they went when they disap
              peared. He was an ideal servant.
              Born in a small Michigan commun
              ity he went to Chicago to make his
              fortune. Chicago was about to have
              a world's fair in commemoration of
              the. discovery of America.
              It was a good town to go to,
              thought Quinlan. An honest Irish
              young man, hla only thought of mak
              ing a living was by honest hard
              work. That Is why he went to work
              for Holmes and worked so wllllng
              ly and so faithfully. The other day
              w hen he drank the fatal potion he
              was middle-aged and broken in
              health. He looked as though he had
              been carried to the point of death
              by tho ghosts of the slain women of
              the castlo ho helped to build.
              It is said by some of his best
              friends that he often reproarhed
              himself for his part In the affair.
              Ho blamed himself for not suspect
              ing Holmes and turning him up to
              the police. Yet he could not bo
              blamed. Every thing in Holmes Cas
              tle seemed to be right. There was
              no sign of murder there. Every
              thing was quiet and still. The rooms
              were lined with asbestos and the
              dying victims never made a sound
              that reached the outsldo world.
              There at night In tho dark house
              they met their death.
              Some of them wero asphyxiated.
              It la believed. Others wore stabbed.
              -'anlBwtSsH Mm
              -
              BnPf mil
              LT WmW ttMBMBSGv
              Others were shot, according to the
              opinions of investigator. No one
              knows. Holmes knew and the vic
              tims perhaps could tell harrowing
              tales if they could talk, but theyr are
              gone and Holmes has been hung for
              his crimes, so In this world no one
              ever will know.
              How many crimes Holmes devised
              no one can tell. Tho first thing to
              attract the attention of tho world
              was the sudden, horrible death of
              B. F. PSetzel. a ihemlst. in Phila
              delphia He died In such a man
              ner that It seerued ho had been
              making chemical experiments and
              had met with an accident Mien his
              chemicals exploded. Holme-, whoso
              right name was Herman "W. Mucl
              cett, telegraphed to St Louis to the
              homo of Mrs Pletzcl and told her to
              rome to Philadelphia and Identify
              the body.
              It is alleged that Holmes met Mrs.
              Pletzel and informed her the body
              was not that of her husband but
              that her husband had his life in
              sured for 10. 000.
              "He's saf- in Canada." Holmes
              told Mrs Pletzel. "He had itim
              frame up this body. It Is t-o badly
              mangled by the explosion that no
              one can ever recognize it Tou
              identify it and we 11 get the insur
              ance. Your husband said for me to
              gl e you half and bring the otner
              half to him."
              Mrs Pletzel later confessed that
              she Identifcd the body without be
              lieving it was that of her husband.
              She thought it was a big swindle
              game on the part of her husband
              and she entered into it readily She
              brought her three children. Alice,
              Nellie and Howard with her. Alice
              was 15 years old. Holmes sepa
              rated her from her children and
              took them to Toronto, Canada,
              Later the bodies, of Alice and
              Nellie were found In the cellar of a
              building Holmes had occupied at
              Toronto.
              I IP FROM CROOK
              RJB E ALED HOLMES.
              Marian Hedgepeth is the man who
              drat directed attention to Holmes.
              Holmes was conducting a drug atoro
              In St Louis when he was arrested on
              a minor charge and placed In jail.
              There ho met Marion Hedgepeth,
              noted as an out and out criminal.
              Holmes asked Hcdgepeth to tell him
              the name of some St, Louis lawyer
              who could give him assistance In
              putting over an Insurance swindle.
              r SBSibBBB ""SBBwPlP f" jySilK hH TV " mm
              ITPPER LEFT H. H.
              Holmes. Upper right
              Holmes Castle. Below
              j Patrick Quinlan.
              Hedgepeth said he gave him the
              name. In return Hedgepeth was to
              get $500. The swindle was con
              summated. That is Pletzel was
              killed in Philadelphia in order to col
              let the Insurance, but Hedgepeth got
              no money.
              Then Hedgepeth notified Chief of
              Police Harrlgan of St. Louis that he
              had "the biggest insurance swindle
              case the police ever had to deal
              with anywhere, anytime in the
              world'
              He sent that message to Harrlgan
              October 9. 1894. Pietzel had died
              September 3. 1894. That failure to
              deal squarely with Hedgepeth is
              doubtless what cost Holmes his
              liberty and life and checked his
              long career of crime. Police at
              once set out to hunt for him. The
              Philadelphia death of Pietzel had
              caused them some wonder, but tho
              word from Hedgepeth made them
              doubly cure of crime. They trailed
              Holmes to Toronto, where the
              bodies of Alice and Nellie Pletzel
              were found. Later they found the
              body of Howard In Indianapolis and
              Identified it as that of Howard, be
              cause of some peculiar playthings
              he had. His body had been burned
              In a stove and the bones alone were
              left Intact.
              Holmes was found In Boston and
              arrested. He was going under tho
              name of Howard there. He was ar
              rested July 14. 1895.
              Mrs. Pletzel told her part in the
              afflr and tried to atone by fisht
              lng for the conviction of the man
              who had made her a widow and
              had slain three of her beautiful
              children.
              In Chicago the record of Holmes
              was looked up. When he was un
              der arrest in Philadelphia awaiting
              trial for the death of Pletzel word
              .ame from all parts of tho United
              Slates that Holmes, or a man an
              swering his description, had taken
              women from their town and the
              unfortunates had never been heard
              from
              From Fort Worth came the In
              formation that Miss Minnie Wil
              liams and her sister, Anna, had
              been led away by Holmes several
              years before and no one had ever
              heard of them. It was found that
              Miss Minnie Williams had entered
              Holmes castlo under the supposi
              tion that she was to be the wife of
              the arch-slayer. She sent to Fort
              Worth for her sister. Anna, to be
              a bridesmaid at the w:diing.
              The sisters had JG0.000 worth
              of property In Forth Worth. They
              were induced to borrow heavily on
              the property and that Is the last
              anyone heard of them. Minnie, the
              bride-elect, died before the wedding
              In Holmes Castle Anna, the brides-mald-to-be.
              also died without ever
              having a chance to wear her bridal
              clothes What happened to tho
              bodies no one knows for certain.
              In the fine of the chimney, whlh
              led from the big stove on the top
              floor, hair was found. It Is believed
              that the hair was that of the sisters
              as It corresponded to their hair The
              theory was advanced at the time
              that the sisters were thrown Into the
              stove and burned. The suction of
              the flue carried the hair up In the
              flue, where it remained as mute evi
              dence against Holmes.
              From Davenport, Io., came an
              other story of disappearance and
              Holmes name was linked with that
              too. Mrs.v Julia Connor and her
              daughter were the missing ones.
              BEAUTIFUL WOMAN
              AND DAUGHTER LOST.
              For more than three years prior
              to 1 895, Mrs. Julia 1 Connor and
              her daughter, Pearl, had been mlss-
              ing from their friends in Iowa.
              Mrs. Connor had gone to Chicago
              v.ith her husband and daughter to
              work in a drug store conducted by
              Holmes. The drug store failed and
              Holmes gave the property to Con
              nor. Mrs. Connor was so taken with
              his generosity that she ceased to
              love her husband. She returned to
              Davenport and Connor obtained a
              divorce.
              Then she returned to Chicago, os
              tensibly to open a boarding house
              in Chicago or the suburbs. She and
              hor daughter never were heard of
              again. When Holmes was arrested
              in Philadelphia, relatives of Julia
              Connor claimed he killed her.
              Many bones wero found around
              Holmes Castle. He explained they
              were beef bones. He explained that
              the flat had been used as a restau
              rant during the World's Fair at Chi
              cago and that much meat was used
              there. He explained that the huge
              dumb waiter was used to convey
              food. He explained that the as
              bestos was to make the house fire
              proof and to keep out cold.
              He had an excuse for everything.
              He admitted he was crooked. He
              explained that he went to Toronto
              to smuggle furs into the United 111?!
              States. He admitted knowing alt
              the women ho was accused of mur-
              dering He admitted knowing Piet- Ewg
              zel. He denied killing any of them. H&l
              Damaging evidence against him Bb
              were buttons of the women he was KhI
              charged with killing, which were
              found in his castle. bIH
              But the defense of Holmes netted LH
              him nothing. He swung from the hI
              gallows for his crimes.
              Though Holmes paid for his mis- jlfl
              deeds with death, Qulnlan suffered Bl
              much more than he. He was ar- LH
              rested with Holmes but freed.
              When he went back to his Mlchl- W
              gan home he found himself the cen- Btf
              ter of eyes Everywhere he went he
              was stared at or else he felt he B .
              was stared at. While the rest of K'
              the world forgot Holmes, the little Be- ' .
              town Where he lived always re- K ''
              hearsed the story. .
              No wonder the honest Irish Janl- flk I
              tor finally picked up a piece of paper H
              and wrote, "I could not sleep." No 'K I
              wonder that after writing that slm- I
              pie line which told a story of nine- Q
              teen years of suffering and horror, E
              that he took poison and ended it R
              all. Hfc
                      
          
          
          </text>
        </result>


      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88063294/1943-10-10/ed-1/seq-81/ocr/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
            THERE was no sudden flash of lightning,
            no sound of demoniac trumpets, no sul
            len roll of thunder to announce to the
            world that a dark prince was horn when, on
            the 16th of May in 1660. a country doctor at
            Gilmanton, New Hampshire, wrote into the
            birth records the name of Herman Mudgett.
            In school young Mudgett was remembered
            for a certain precocity; a deft hand and lumi
            nous black eyes. At sixteen he, himself, was
            schoolmaster, and two years later, considered
            the "catch” of the region, he courted, won and
            married the "local belle”—Clara Lovering
            Her family had money and in 1679 her
            father, impressed with Herman's mental abil
            ity. willingly sent the young couple to Ann
            Arbor, where Mudgett wished to study medi
            cine at the University of Michigan.
            If he played practical jokes in the dissect,
            ting room and unmercifully hazed other Fresh
            men with "spare parts” and. skeletons, it was
            put down as the exut* ntiee and
            enthusiasm of a budding genius
            Rut in his Sophomore year Mudgett
            hatched a high-jinx that no amount i
            of toleration could regard as a prank A
            A fellow student was insured for
            $1 000 with Mudgett the beneficiary
            Then a cadaver was stolen from the Wj
            medical school and planted as the
            dead body of the insured.
            Mudgett had the supf*>sed body of
            fi tend taken from a <h<ap room-
            : g house to a second rate funeral
            • arlor The underwriters accepted
            the unsuspecting
            undertaker's cer
            tificate and paid.
            Laughing to
            !mai< if, Mudgett
            picketed the
            1 '>oo. notified his
            w ife he was called
            to California on a
            ■ secret mission”
            ar.d to go hark to
            New Hampshire
            and wait for him.
            She waa lucky.
            In a young
            man calling him
            self H H Holmes
            opened a pharmacy
            in midtown Phila
            delphia. He had
            dark, luminous
            eyes and a pleas
            ing way with
            women His drug
            store was an im
            mediate success.
            In 1 883. or there-
            A bouts, there ap
            peared in Chicago
            a I>r H H Holmes,
            1 um i noil s - e y e d.
            soft-spoken and ob-
            viously well off. who purchased a three-story
            corner building on 63rd Street, a substantial
            property with stores on the ground fl«»or.
            apartments upstairs, overhanging bastion
            upper windows and a corner apothecary shop.
            It had a vaguely sinister look, even before
            the impressive-looking doctor bought it
            Dr. Holmes reserved the upper floors of
            this castle for himself. The drugstore he
            rented to I L. Connor, who had a pretty wife
            and an infant daughter, Gertrude. Mr. and
            Mrs Connor especially Mrs Connor- thought
            Dr. Holmes a charming landlord.
            He spent a lot of energy installing modern
            plumbing, putting down floors, tearing out
            walls, constructing a third-floor laboratory.
            Much of this work he did himself and
            (somewhat to buxom Mrs. Connor’s envy)
            included among the installations a blond sei -
            retary. Miss Emily Cigrand.
            During the next~four years a prosperous
            Herman Holmes operated a chain of small
            drugstores through the Middle West.
            Tn St. Louis kindly Dr. Holmes became
            interested in a shabby drug clerk named Ben
            jamin Pitezel who had four small children
            and an ailing (but pretty) wife.
            Generously the doctor put Pitezel in charge
            of his St. Louis stores while he commuted
            between St. Louis and Chicago.
            Some time during this period of expansion
            the good doctor raised a glossy, blue-black
            beard. Too, on one of his returns to Chicago
            he told Mrs. Connor that Miss Cigrand had
            left, and ho was seeking a new secretary.
            So. presently, there was a new face in tho
            home office on 63rd Street--that of Minnie
            Williams, a pretty Texas girl.
            In a chain of letters to her sister Nettie,
            in Fort Worth, she confessed that she was
            falling in love. In 1893 Minnie invited Nettie
            to Chicago. Dr. Holmes, it appeared, wouldn’t
            think of leading her to the altar unless her
            rister were on hand to witness the ceremony.
            Nettie journeyed to Chicago forthwith The
            \ . edding was quiet hut beautiful. Dr. Holmes
            crnrcMi
            The Sinister "Castle” on »>3rd Street in < bit ago
            Which the Knterprising Medical Student Turned
            Druggist Transformed Into a Murder Factory.
            jMj? ■ < jpflf of a*
            v >v f MmM « W Wm J| JbSh^
            tMMR' juL , flj i/\
            MLk H M BHIi fll 1 I ft ft **Wr JU*
            o*r», »m m
            made such a thoughtful
            husband and brother-in
            law.
            So thought Mrs. Con
            nor one day when she was
            downstairs alone and the
            doctor strolled in to col
            lect the rent.
            ”1 haven’t seen Minnie
            and Nettie all week Are
            they away?" she asked.
            The doctor nodded, pet
            ting his glossy b< ard
            "They’ve gone on a long
            trip to Canada.” He re
            garded plump Mrs Con
            nor with his dreamv, lu-
            ruinous eyes. Then. “I wonder if you would
            like to he my secretary.”
            Tn 1894 a Philadelphia paper carried an
            account of a ''mysterious chemical explosion ”
            An amateur inventor calling at the office
            of “B. t\ Perry Patents Bought and Sold’’
            in a dingy building on Callow hill Street was
            shocked to find the pa**nt attorney dead on
            the* floor, his features burned beyond recog
            nition and the room strewn with charred
            papers, broken glass and other wret kage
            The inventor rushed for the police
            The bluecoats decided Perry had been killed
            during an experiment with some sort of «x
            --plosive. Then, searching his effects they
            could find no business papers, no means of
            identification other than the name on his door.
            Detectives Frank Geyer and Thomas Craw*
            ford, assigned to the case, found other mys
            teries. Although the face was destroyed as
            though by volatile and or chemic al, the body
            lay in an attitude of composure.
            Among shattered test tubes and parapher
            nalia. they found the victim's pmc neatly
            loaded with tobacco. A box of matches had
            not been ignited by tho blast
            “Funny nolmdy in the neighborhood heard
            it,” Geyer remarked
            And on top of that, the pest mm em it-
            m
            Minnie Wiliams, One of
            the Doctor’* lamg String
            of Sec retaries.
            vealed chloroform in the victim’s stomach.
            Geyer and Crawford were suspicious, but
            the coroner’s verdict was “death- induced by
            explosion, probably suicide."
            One Week after the burial in potter
            field, the authorities received a letter from a
            Chicago lawyer. Jeptha Howe, asserting that
            I’errv was tho professional name of Benjamin
            F. Pitezel, an experimental chemist that a
            SIO,OOO insurance award whs due his widow
            who would presently arrive in Philadelphia to
            identify her husband's remains.
            In a few* days the tardy claimants arrived.
            Mrs Carrie Pitezel. described as ill, was r.< f
            in the party, which included Lawyer How* .
            little Alice Pitezel. and a “friend of the
            family." a Dr. H. H. Holmes.
            In tears, fourteen-year-old Alice had diffi
            culty recognizing the disinterred corpse, but
            friend Holmes spoke up quietly. “If it’s poor
            Pitezel. he’ll have a mole on his left shoulder
            blade!”
            The identifying mole was found.
            Just as Lawyer Howe. Alice and H\l: *s
            were leaving the morgue, the amateur inven
            tor who had discovered the body happened in
            and gazed suspiciously after Holmes.
            "Funny.” he told Detective Geyer "I’d
            swear I saw that gaunt, bearded fellow in th*-
            dead mans office a few days before the
            C IMS, t>y A n Week la Great Britain Rights 1
            % j| '•L lpy y "• tr- *§’ 1 Jw^^PW^^P^MWWW|WW^W>WffWy
            7k W§r v A > v °v j, ; " '■if *
            Finally Came tin Day When the Girl's Suave Employer Ushered Her Gallantly Down the Stairs.
            At Their Foot She Paused, Transfixed. Many Things Became to Her in That One Revealing
            Instant—But As Ear As She Has Concerned Her Knowledge Had Come Too Tate!
            a.
            ’ '-4 w « 1 . rngm
            tit njamin Pltexel, Holmes’
            Assistant —in More
            Ways Than One.
            yliiliMk raffipgjJL
            Alice, Benjamin’s Child,
            Whom the Doctor
            .After—Too Well.
            him the money. Out of her husband’s insur
            ance, that left her exactly S2OO.
            As always. Holmes was generous. He told
            Mrs. Pitezel to travel on this money to Bur
            lington. Vermont, with her youngest child and
            new baby. He would keep Alice, Nellie and
            Howard, the oldest children, in his rare until
            Mrs. Pitezel could rjiove into a house he owned
            in Burlington. Mrs. Pitezel obeyed
            Poor Alice, Nellie and toddling Howard set
            out for what he called his "castle in Chicago."
            This was in October, 1894.
            Mrs. I, L Connor. Incidentally, who had
            separated from her husband to become the
            doctor’s secretary, was no longer at the Chi
            cago address. Neither was her little daughter.
            Meanwhile Detectives Geyer and Crawford
            had received a startling communication from
            Mrs Pitezel in Vermont and summoned h* r to
            Philadelphia immediately.
            Mrs. Pitezel told them an appalling
            story. Holmes was a master swindler, she
            asserted! Substituting medical cadavers for
            insured accomplices, he’d made a fortune on
            fraudulent death claims. He had Induced
            her husband to take part in such a fraud, but
            she was afraid no substitution had been made!,'
            "He keeps writing to me that Ben is in
            hiding But his 1« tters are evasive. I know
            he murdered 'ihn! And Uc w *x)t my three
            fatal explosion.”
            , The detectives
            didn’t like the smell
            of it Against their
            private advice, how
            ever. the life insur
            ance company mailed
            a check for SIO,OOO
            to widowed Carrie
            Pitezel.
            Dr Holmes had
            an.irved to meet
            Mrs. Pitezel in St.
            Ivtniis where the check
            was cashed and
            $2 800 paid to Law
            yer Howe. Then, in
            a confidential talk
            with Mrs. Pitezel,
            Holmes revealed an
            unpaid debt of $7,000
            against her husband.
            He advised Mrs. Pite
            z« 1 to let him handle
            this, and she gave
            oldest children with him in Chicago 1”
            Geyer and Crawford were inclined to share
            Mrs. Pitezel’* fears as they set out to locate
            Dr. Holmes and the children. The trail was
            a snake-track, but by dogged persistence, aided
            by the postal authorities, they traced his
            career from Mudgett to medical king with
            the gloomy ’’castle’’ in Chicago.
            On the way they found little Howard in a
            house in Indianapolis, his tiny body stuffed up
            a fireplace chimney.
            They learned Holmes owned the house, but
            if was not until they broke into the Chicago
            < ,i*tle that they knew they were dealing with
            the century’s worst mass murderer.
            There they found a sound-proofed chamber,
            surgical tools and torture instruments.
            A trap door in the hathroom led down to a
            secret oubliette in the cellar. There, in a
            furnace and under the floor, they found the
            bones and charred remnants of the Williams
            sisters, Mrs. Connor, children, wives and sec
            retaries. There was evidence to indicate he
            had sold Miss Cigrand s skeleton to a medical
            academy!
            It was not difficult to picture the suave
            Holmes ushering his victim* gallantly down
            the stairs to have them pause, transfixed, as
            many things became clear to them in one re
            vealing instant.
            The detectives redoubled their effort.
            Holmes, they learned, had departed for
            Vermont. And there they arrested the livid
            man; he had gone Fast to wipe out the re
            mainder of the Pitezel family!
            No one knows or will ever know the total
            of his killings. Taken to Philadelphia, he con
            fessed to two murders a year over a period of
            approximately fourteen years.
            Blubbering in his beard, he went to the
            Moyamensing Prison gallows on May 7. 1895
            Then, lethal to the eyes blazing, he pro
            nounced a curse on all the persons who had
            contributed to hia downfall.
            Within a year the prison warden, the
            coroner, the undertaker who embalmed him,
            and the Jury foreman were dead, l ie follow
            ing year the hangman fell dead, another
            juryman committed suicide, and the prie.
            who heard his confession was found dead ir an
            alley with a fractured skull. And in 1912 De
            tective Crawford, laughing at a joke about
            Holmes, himself fell dead
            ’ Up until Hitler, historians considered the
            Roman Emperor, Caligula, the foulest man
            of all time They overlooked Herman Mudgett.
            THU AMlllim WliliKLV

        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1914-09-12/ed-1/seq-32/ocr/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>LONG LOST MYSTERY SOLVED IN
          FINDING OF BONES?
          The police believe that a mystery
          of 20 years' standing was solved
          when Wm. Raelz, plowing his farm
          near Momence, HI., uncovered the
          bodies of two men and a girl.
          The girl is thought to have been
          Minnie Williams, third bigamous wife
          of Herman Webster Mudgett, alias H.
          H. Holmes, slayer of twelve.
          She disappeared while living in the
          "castle" of Holmes at 61st and Wal
          lace sts. After Holmes' death on a
          Philadelphia scaffold a. search for her
          was begun, but her body was not
          found.</text>
      </result>
  
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92051227/1922-12-18/ed-1/seq-14/ocr/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>CAPTAIN H. H. HOLMES
        noted international polo ret
        eree, has sailed to referee
        match at Cannes, France, be
        tween Lord Rocksavage's Brit
        ish tam and King of Spain's
        tour. (Int'l Newsreel.)</text>
      </result>
  
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83040198/1907-09-27/ed-1/seq-5/ocr/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>
                    Holmes.
            Scarf for head, . first, Mr. Col.
            Greene.'
            Silk mittons, first, Mrs. Jessie
            Dunn, second, Mrs. L. F. .Tiler.
            Wool mittens, first, Mrs. S. A.
            Vosburg, second, Mrs. F. H.
            Miller.
            Bedspread, first, Mrs. H. H.
            Holmes, second, Mrs. P. Horn.
            Skirt first, Mrs II H. II lmes.
            Leggins, first, Mrs. A. II.
            Johnson.
            Slippers, first 'Mrs. L. F. Tvler.
            second, Mrs. Col Greene.
            Stand, cover, first Mrs. Perry
            Horn.
            Baby sox and baby shoes, first
            Mrs. H. H. Holmes.
            Point lace Bertha, first Mrs.
            JV. Winstead, second, Mrs. Anna
            Knox.
            Same, collar, first, Miss Beulah
            lentz, second Mrs. G. A. Pratt
            Same, display, first Mrs Ed
            Panning, second, Miss Beulah
            Slentz.
            Same, infant cap. first Miss
            Julia Miller, second, Mrs A H
            Johnson
            Ladies lace handkerchief, home
            made, first, Mrs A D Buckland.
            second, Mrs L Honnen.
            Ladies lace handkerchief. Honi-
            ton, first, Mrs. C. H. Peters.
            Same, drawn work, first Mrs.
            H. H. Holmes, second. Mrs.
            John Moffatt
            Same, crochet, also crochet pil
            low cases, first, Mrs. A. D. Buck-
            land.
            Cross work sofa pillow, first.
            Miss Mamie Bartels.
            Battenberg center piece, first
            Miss Leona Griffith. second, Mrs.
            W. Winstead.
            Same, table cover, first Miss
            Beulah Slentz, second.' Mrs. Ed.
            Panning.
            Same, lunch cloth, first Mrs.
            Ed. Panning, second, Mrs. W.
            Winstead.
            Same, sofa pillow, first, Mrs.
            W. Winstead.
            Same, piano scarf, first, Mrs.
            Ed Panning, second, Mrs. C. H.
            Peters.
            Drawn work display, first, Mrs.
            Anna Knox, second, Mrs. X. L.
            Weisenberger
            Point lace center piece, first,
            Mrs. Ed Panning.
            Drawn work bib, first, Trissa,
            Mause.
            Point lace handkerchief, first,
            Mrs. L. Seeber, second, Mrs.
            Robert Ewalt.
            Knotted lace shawl, first Ella
            Wesley
            Knit robe for baby cab, first,
            Mrs. II. II. Holmes.
            Dresser scarf, first,' Mrs. L.
            Seeber, second, Mrs. W. F. Gra
            ham.
            Ladies underwear display, first,
            Mrs. S. A. Cone.
            Lunch clotniirst, Miss Buelah
            Slentz, second, Mrs. E. W. Sew
            ard.
            Tray cloth, first, Mrs. C. H.
            Peters, second, Mrs Clemmie
            Dodge.
            Center piece, first, Miss Leona
            Griffith, second, Mrs. C. A.
            Weltmer.
            Doilies, six, first, Mrs. John
            Moffatt, second, Mrs. Don Dodge.
            Cross stitch, first, Mrs. Fred
            Hfmker, second, Mrs. F. II.
            Miller.
            Mount Mellick center piece,
            first, Mrs. E.JW. Seward, second,
            Mrs. M. Weirauch.
            Same, lunch cloth, first, Mrs.
            I. N. Wilhide, second, Mrs. L.
            Honnen.
            Sam?, "doily, first, Mrs. D. A.
            Weltmer, second, Mrs. Rooert
            hwait
            Bulgarian table cover, first,
            Miss Beulah Slentz, second, Mrs.
            A. L. Sellers.
            Mt Mellick table cover and nap
            kins first, Mrs L. F. Tyler.
            Silk embroidery on flannel, first,
            Mrs Chas. Lundblade, second,
            Mrs. H. H. Holmes.
            Shirt waist, wallachian, first,
            Mrs. G. E. Wyman.
            Drawn work lunch clotfi, first,
            Mrs. Chas. Sipes, second, Miss
            Georgia Walker.
            Same, center piece, first, Anna
            Knox, second, Mrs. Belle Hotch
            kiss.
            Same, side board scarf, first,
            Mrs. Joe McMulIen, - second,
            Aletha Bailey.
            Same, doilies, six, first, Mrs F
            S Mitchell, second, Mrs John
            Moffatt
            Ca tinned k Best wtek'kiMoe
            h SOLICITS
            I YOUR ACCOUNT!
            I X7JH.a large</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87068097/1890-06-18/ed-1/seq-3/ocr/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>
              
                      Proposals for the iraurovettWiit of Bright Street,
        frem Jersey Avenue to Brunswick Street, km (10» in
        number, were presented as fioMonvs:
        i,orc t>pndeverycubic vard.of earth estivation
        \ nr |. ldc.; '. H. Holmes, 5c.; >t. Carlev, lc ;
        UiMrt llt xd, 6o.; O’Douuell A Umittiy. ltxsa
        •7m. Kramer, loj P. J. Condon, lc.; Thomas CarajL
        wh, 15c.; Charles O’Nelil. 20c.; Henry & McGivuey ,
        §0»
        For each and every cubicyoard of earth fllPng—M»
        iluilery, 30c.; H. H. Holmes, 35c.; M. Curley. lot
        rnomiis Harrington, 12c.: O’Donnell A Ormsby, 1804
        Wm. Kramer, 80c.; P. J. Condon, lc.: Thomas Cavan
        igh, 10c.; Charles O'Neill, 10c.; Henry A McGlvney,
        For each and every cubic yard of sand or gravel
        filling—M Muliery, 9uc.;H. fl. Holmes, $1; M. GUI«
        ley, $1; Thomas Harrington, *1 4t»; O’Donnell 4$
        Ormsby, 00c., Wm. Kramer, $1: P.. J. Conttoa, $1;
        Thomas Cavanagh, $1; Charles O'Neill. 00c { Henry &
        HeGivney, lie.
        </text>
      </result>

        <result>
          <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85036014/1890-08-31/ed-1/seq-6/ocr/</id>
          <rel>0</rel>
          <text>
                              OPENING OP SEALED PROPOSALS.
              Proposals lor improvement of sidewalks on Monk*
              sromerv Sweet, from Bergen to West Side avenues,
              nine (fl) in number, wore presented, as foiTows:
              For eacn and every cubic yard of earth excava
              tion—Frank Hail lflc., Joseph H. Outlay 30c., Dohr
              man & Curley 36c.. H. H. Holmes lc., Henry Byrne
              30c., Thomas Harrington 26c., Wo. Kramer 4.0c.,
              (J’Donnell A Ormsby 20c.
              For each and every cubic yard of earth filling—
              Frank Hall 19c. Joseph H. Cutley 46c., Dohrman A
              Curley 46c., H. H. Hoiroe* 30c.. Henry Bvrn«* 00c.,
              Thomas Harr me ton 46c., Wm. Kramer 46c., O’Don*
              cell A Ormsoy 4oc.
              For each and every ruble yard of sane or gravel
              •Wing—Frank Hall fl. Joseph H. Cutley 65e., Do&r*.
              man A Curley II 76, H. H. Holmes 50c., Henry
              Byrne fl 26, Thomas Harrington fl 49, Wiu.
              Kramer t'2, O’Donnell & Ormsby fl 60.
              For each and every square loot of new flagging—
              Frank Hall 18c.. Joseph H. Cutley I6*ic.. Doorman
              A Curley 22Hsc.. H. H. Holmes 16c.. Henry Bvnn
              19c.. Thomas Harrington lflc., Wm. Kramer 22c,
              O’Donnell & Ormsby 21c.
              For each and everv square footrf rdaM flagging—
              Frank Hall 3c. Joseph £j. Cutley 2c.. Dohrman A
              Curlev 5e.. H. H. Holmes 82c., Henry Byrne 3c
              Thomas Harrington 3c., Wm, Kramer 6c., O Donneu
              & Ormsby 6c.
              The bid of Michael Mullery was thrown out as
              Informal.
              Proposals for the improvement of Imng Street
              from Central Avenue to Nelson Avenue, ten in num
              ter, were received as follows:
              For each and every cubic varrf of earth excavation
              -John Tolly 30c., Henry Byrne 36c., Frank flsll 20c..
              R. D. Holmes 30c., F. .T. Condon 40c., Wm. Kramer
              J6c„ Dohrman & Curley 46c., O’Donnell Jfc Ormsby
              For each and every cubic, vard of rock excavation
              -John Tally ft 60. Henry Byrue $3. Frank Hall fl,
              H. H. Holmes fl, P. J. Condon 6c.. Wm. Kramer fl,
              Dohrman A Curley le., O’Donnell A Ormsby ioc.
              For eacn ana every cubic yard of earth filling*^
              John Tuny lOc., Henry Byrne 20c.. Frank Hall 10c.,
              R. H. Holmes 6c., P. J. Condon 10c., Wm. Kramer
              16c., Dohrman A Curley lflo, O'Donnell & Ormsby
              •be,
              ^or ea^h and every cubic yard or sand and grovel
              in*—John Tally 90c.. Henry Byrne fl 26, Frank
              *1J, *1 9,». H. H. Holmes 00c., P. J. Condon fl 50l
              . m. Kramer $2, Dohrman A Curley f 160, O’Donnell
              4c Ormsby fl 90.
              For each and every square foot of new bridge
              stone—Jenn TuUv 40c., Henry Bvrne 40c., Frank
              Hall fl, H. H. Holmes 60c.f P. J. Condon 60c.. Wm.
              Kramer 05c., Dohrman A Curley 80c., O’Donnell A
              Ormsby 06c.
              For each and every square foot of new flagging—
              John Toil? 17a, H«nrv Bvrne20c., Frank H»H 17c.,
              H. H. Holmes, 17c., P. J. Condon 19c.. Wm, Kramer
              81c., Dohrman & Curley 21c., O’Donnell & Ormsby
              80c.
              for each and everv square-foot of rela’d flagging
              —John Tuliy 2c., Henrv Byrne 3c., Frank Hall 2c.,
              H. H. Holmes lc., P. J. Condon 6c., Wm. Kramer 4c.,
              Dohrman A Curley oc , O’Donnell Sc Ormsbv 3c.
              The bids of Henrv Schneider and Michael Mullery
              were thrown out as informal.
              Propose Is for ihs improvement of Water Avenue,
              from Montgomery Street to Vroora Street, eight (8)
              in number, were proseated, as follows:
              For each and every cubic Vard of earth excavation
              —Frank Hall 20c., H. H. Holmes 30c., Henrv Byrno
              30c.. James F. Wheel than 28c., Joan Nolan 36c.,
              O’Donnell AOrmsby45c., Donrmaa A Curley 38c..
              Michael Mullery 40c.
              For eacn and every cubic ya d of rock excavation
              —Frank Hall lc., li. H. Holmes fl. Renrv Byrne
              •2 60, James F. Wheellhan lc., John Nolan 6c..
              O’Donnell & Ormsby 10c., Dohrman A Curley lc.,
              Michael Mullery $3.
              For each and every cubit vard of earth filling—
              Frank Hall lc., H. H. Holmes 10c.. Henry Byrnt
              16o.. James F. W haelihan JLOc.. John Nolan 14c..
              O’Donnell A Orn
              Michael Mullery 2oc.
              For ea'-h and every cubic yard of sand or gravel
              fllllng-Frank Ball II 40, ii. H. Holmes 11. Henrv
              Byrne II 20, James f\ wbeeliban $139, John Nolan
              *1 60, O’Donnell A Ormsby $1 52, Dohrman A Curley
              11 76. Michael Muliery fl 62.
              For each and every square foot of paving—Fran k
              Bail II 40. H. H. Holmes |1 40, Henry Byrne #1 40.
              James F. Wheellhan fl 34. John Nolan fl 60. O’Don
              nell A Ormsby fl 66, Dohrman A Curley $160,
              Michael Mullery fl 66.
              For each and everv lineal foot of new curb stone—
              Frank HaT 40c., H. H Bonnes 60c.. Htnry Byrne
              *6c., James F. Wneeilnon 53c., John Nolan 66c.r
              O’Donnell A Ormsby 63c., Dohrman O Curley 00c..
              Micnael Muliery 68c.
              For each and every square foot of bridge stone—
              Frank Hall Sfl. H. H. Holmes 60c., Henrv Byrne 48c.
              James F. Wheellhan 4Sc.. John Nolan 70c., O'Don
              nell A Ormsby 70c., Doorman A Curley 89c„ Michael
              Mullery C8c.
              bur each and every square foot of new flagging—
              Frank Hall 17c., H. H. Holmes 18c., Henry Byrne
              18c., James F. Wheellhan 17c., Joun Nolan 17c,,
              O’Donnell & Ormsby 22c„ Dohrman A Curley
              Michael Mullery 20c.
              For each and everv square yard of repaving—
              Frank Hall lc., Q. H. Hoi mss lc., Henry Byrne 16c..
              James F. Wheellhan 10c.. John Nolan 2oc.. O’Don
              nell A Ormsby 5c„ Doorman A Curley 40., Michael
              Mullery 20c.
              For eac*» and every lineal foot of reset curb stone
              -frank Hall lc., H. li Holmes6c.. Henry Byrna
              3c., John F Wbeelihan 7c., John Nolan 5c., O'Don
              nell A Ormsby lOc., Doorman A Cuney XOc.. Michael
              Mullery 10c.
              For each and every square foot of re’aid bridge
              stone—-Frank Hall lc.. H. H. Holmes lc., Henrv
              Byrne 5c., James F. Wheelman 10c., John Nolan
              5c.. O’Donnell A Or-^by 10c., Donrman A Curley
              10c.. Michael Mullery iv\
              For each and everv sou. re foot ot relaid flagging
              —Frank Halt lc., H. H. Holmes lc.. Hoary Byrne
              Sc., James F. Wbeetiban 3c, Jonn Nolan 5c., O’Don
              nell A Ormsby 6c, Dorman A Curley 6c., Michael
              Mullery 5c.
              For each and every lineal foot of cribbing—Frank
              HaH lc.. a H. lioimes lc , Henry Byrne 40c., Jas.
              F. WhseLihau 18c.. John Nolan 20c., O’Donnell A
              Ormsby 20c., Dohrman A Curley 60c., Michael Mui
              lerv 10c. , _
              For each and every new receiving basin—Frank
              Hail $100. H. H. Holmes lc., Henry Byrne I10J,
              James F. Wheellhan $105, Jonn Nolan $110, O’Don
              nell A Ormsby fl 16. Dohrman A Gurley |120, Mi
              chael Mullery lioo.
              For each and every manhole head brought to
              grade—Frank Hall $10, H. H. Holmes lc., Henry
              Byrne $2. James F. wheellhan 10c., John No.an
              SI, O’Donnell & Ormsby Donrinan A Curley $1,</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045389/1918-09-15/ed-1/seq-7/ocr/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>Edenton, N. C.?H. H. Holmes Co.
          Fayetteville, N. C.?B. Fleishman & Bros.
          Goldsboro, N. C.?M. E. Castex & Co.
          Greensboro, N. C.?The Meyers Co.
          Kingston, N. C.?T. TV. Newborn.
          Newbern, N. C.?S. Lipman Dept. Store.
          Raleigh, X. C.?Kaplan Bros. Co.
          Salisbury, N. C.?D. Oustreictaer.
          Smithfield. N. C.?W. L. Woodal & Sons.
          Thomasville, N. C.? L. W. Elliott.
          Wilmington, X. C.?C. II. Fore & Co.
          Winston-Salem, N. C.?J. N. Davis Co.</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92070146/1934-10-04/ed-1/seq-6/ocr/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>
                  HOLTVILLE
            Modem Grocery &. Mkt.
            The Grocerteria
            S • A awashima
            Bessie Wofford
            Consumers Supply
            Nell’s Drive-In Market
            H. H. Holmes
            Hop Lee Co.
            MELOLAND
            Meloland Store
            SEELEY
            Seeley Mercantile Co.
            T. A. Howard
            Hong Sur* Co.
            IMPERIAL
            Lincoln’s
            Morris Grocery
            Webb s Grocery
            IMPERIAL VALLEY PRESS, EL CENTRO, CALIFORNIA, THURSDAY, OCTOBER 4. 1931</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92067106/1920-01-15/ed-1/seq-5/ocr/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text>
                  You are hereby notified that Mr.
          Robert R. Gibson, a representative ot
          the Federal Board of Vocational Edu
          cation, District Vocational office at
          Denver, Colorado, will be In Buffalo on
          Friday and Saturday, January 23d and
          34th, and he desires to get in touch
          with all disabled soldiers, sailors and
          marines and nurses, whose disability
          incurred in, aggravated by, or trace
          able to their service in the greet wsr,
          are now vocationally handicapped. All
          such are requested to notify
          P. A. Gatchell, Sr.,
          Sec’y Home Service Section, A. R. C.
          or H. H. Holmes,</text>
      </result>


      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90050268/1913-01-02/ed-1/seq-3/ocr/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
                  <text>Mrs. H. H. Holmes is spending the
          •week at Newport with Mrs. McMinn.
          H. H. Holmes is spending this week
          camping in the Black river bottoms.
          I have fresh sweet milk, also skim
          med milk at all times f</text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>



  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-nietzsche</id>
    <results>


      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>


      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>


      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      
    </results>
  </topic>


  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-radium</id>
    <results>

    reading guide 
      1
        <result>
          <id>/https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1903-04-19/ed-1/seq-36/ocr/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      2
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      3
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      4
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      5
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      6
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      7
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      8
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      9
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      10
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>

      11
        <result>
          <id>/</id>
          <rel>1</rel>
          <text></text>
        </result>







    </results>
  </topic>




</topics>
